<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.2.0/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="cdn.land.resort.0001">
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title level="m" type="main">Lake Andes as It Is Viewed Afar</title>
<title level="m" type="sub"></title>
<principal n="Nesheim, David A.">David Nesheim</principal>
</titleStmt>
<editionStmt>
<edition><date>2012</date></edition>
</editionStmt>
<publicationStmt>
<idno>cdn.water.boat.0020</idno>
 <authority>Casting Digital Nets: Fishery Modeling, Native Dispossession, and Dynamic History on the Great Plains</authority>
<distributor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln Libraries</distributor>
<address>
<addrLine>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</addrLine>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
<availability>
<p>Copyright &#169; 2012 by University of Nebraska, all rights reserved.
Items in the Archive may be shared in accordance with the Fair Use provisions
of U.S. copyright law.  Redistribution or republication on other terms, in
any medium, requires express written consent from the editor and advance
notification of the publisher, the Center for Digital Research in the Humanities.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>

<notesStmt>
<note type="summary">

</note>
</notesStmt>


<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="a" type="original">Lake Andes as It Is Viewed Afar</title>
<title level="a" type="original">Editor Spencer News Sees a Splendid Future for the Webfeet</title>
<title level="j">Lake Andes Wave</title>
<author></author>
<publisher></publisher>
<pubPlace></pubPlace>
<date when="1904-09-22"></date>
<biblScope type="page">8</biblScope>
</bibl>
</sourceDesc>

</fileDesc>

<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="water">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="sky">
<term></term>
</keywords>
 <keywords scheme="original" n="land">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="earth">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="keyword">
<term>Streets</term>
</keywords>
</textClass>
</profileDesc>

<revisionDesc>
    <change when="2012-11-14"><name>Laura Weakly</name> Fixed title</change>
    <change when="2010-01-28"><name>Laura Weakly</name> Model Encoding</change>
    <change when="2010-01-25"><name>Sam Herley</name> OCR</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>

<text>


<body>
<head type="main">Lake Andes As It Is Viewed Afar</head>

<head type="sub">Editor Spencer News Sees a Splendid Future for the Webfeet.</head>

<note type="editors">Editor Seifert in his Spencer News last week has this to say of his 
visit here:</note>
    
<p>"Last Friday morning, accompanied by our little son Harry, we started
on a little trip to Lake Andes, in Charles Mix. * * * We got to Tyndall
finally and transferrred onto the 'Squaw Central," and at 6:15 arrived
at Lake Andes, where we were met by our old friend Phil McGuire, the
section foreman, whose residence was left two and one-half miles out
whom the present town of Lake Andes was located, and as yet the 
Milwaukee railroad company, as Mr. McGuire expressed it, 'has not felt
able to move it to the town.' Mr. McGuire and his estimable family 
entertained us in the finest style, and did everything to make our
stay pleasant, and to say that we greatly enjoyed their hospitality
would be putting it entirely too mildly.</p>
    
   <p>"We spent the time while there in hunting and fishing with the
usual hunters' luck. The lake is a beautiful sheet of water from a 
half to a mile wide and 12 miles long. It is fed by two artesian
wells but in by the government, and the water is as clear as crystal
and teeming with fish. The land adjoining the lake is nearly all
'allotment land' that is alloted to the Indians by the government,
but there are quite a few white settlers scattered over the prairie.
Some of the Indians have good houses and cultivate a portion of the 
land but the greater part is used for grazing and hay.</p>
   <p>"The town of Lake Andes, which is only about four months old,
is a specimen of western enterprise, and already has several
hundred inhabitants, three elevators and the fourth one being built,
several general stores, drug store, two barber shops, a newspaper.
The Lake Andes Wave, ably edited by Bro. Fry, and numerous other
business institutions, such as hotels, restaurants, billiard halls,
etc. The town is bound to be a boomer in the near future - and 
probably the county seat at no distant day."</p>
</body>
</text>
</TEI>