<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.2.0/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="cdn.land.resort.0006">
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title level="m" type="main">Lake Andes Good for Hunting, Fishing</title>
<title level="m" type="sub"></title>
<principal n="Nesheim, David A.">David Nesheim</principal>
</titleStmt>
<editionStmt>
<edition><date>2012</date></edition>
</editionStmt>
<publicationStmt>
<idno>cdn.water.boat.0020</idno>
 <authority>Casting Digital Nets: Fishery Modeling, Native Dispossession, and Dynamic History on the Great Plains</authority>
<distributor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln Libraries</distributor>
<address>
<addrLine>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</addrLine>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
<availability>
<p>Copyright &#169; 2012 by University of Nebraska, all rights reserved.
Items in the Archive may be shared in accordance with the Fair Use provisions
of U.S. copyright law.  Redistribution or republication on other terms, in
any medium, requires express written consent from the editor and advance
notification of the publisher, the Center for Digital Research in the Humanities.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>

<notesStmt>
<note type="summary">

</note>
</notesStmt>


<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="a" type="original">Untitled</title>
<title level="a">Lake Andes Good for Hunting, Fishing</title>
<title level="j">Spencer News</title>
<author></author>
<publisher></publisher>
<pubPlace></pubPlace>
<date when="1906-07-05"></date>
<biblScope type="page">5</biblScope>
</bibl>
</sourceDesc>

</fileDesc>

<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="water">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="sky">
<term></term>
</keywords>
 <keywords scheme="original" n="land">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="earth">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="keyword">
<term>Streets</term>
</keywords>
</textClass>
</profileDesc>

<revisionDesc>
    <change when="2012-11-14"><name>Laura Weakly</name> Supplied title</change>
    <change when="2010-02-18"><name>Laura Weakly</name> Initial Encoding</change>
    <change when="2010"><name>Sam Herley</name> OCR</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>

<text>


<body>


<p>Of the many places within easy distance of Sioux City, Mitchell,
and Sioux Falls, for the man in search of good fishing and hunting
grounds, where he can spend his summer vacation, there is probably
no place so little heard of as Lake Andes, South Dakota.
Located in Charles Mix county, but six miles from the old muddy and 
within the borders of the Old Yankton reservation situated a little
village of 500 population, the farming facilities and the soil being
unexcelled. The prosperity of the town, though but two years old, is
attested to by the substantial appearance of its streets, and the 
wide cement sidewalks that extend in every direction. About one half 
mile down a gradual slope lies the west end of the lake, which extends
for fourteen miles, varying in the width from one mile to three in
width. The depth averaging five feet over its entire surface.
It is a common occurance for fishers, after a three or four hours 
trip to come in with from fifty to seventy-five bass, varying in 
weight from two to six pounds, a four or five pound fish being quite
common. While the catches of bull-heads, which many people prefer
for eating on account of their being practically boneless, are 
not spoken of unless they exceed the hundred mark, it being no usual
thing to make two and even three hundred for the day. To those who 
have fished in the worn out lakes of the old advertised resorts, 
the catches here put down may seem erroneous and have a fishy flavor
and nothing but a trial will convince. A good landing and numerous
boats are for hire, while several gasoline launches, one of which
seats over a hundred people ply back and forth over the lake, for the 
convenience of the pleasure seekers. . . .</p>

</body>
</text>
</TEI>