<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.2.0/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="cdn.land.letter.0004">
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title level="m" type="main">Johnson, Ripple, and Dutch correspondence</title>
<title level="m" type="sub"></title>
<principal>David Nesheim</principal>
</titleStmt>

<editionStmt>
<edition><date>2010</date></edition>
</editionStmt>
<publicationStmt>
<idno>cdn.land.letter.0004</idno>
 <authority>Casting Digital Nets: Fishery Modeling, Native Dispossession, and Dynamic History on the Great Plains</authority>
<distributor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln Libraries</distributor>
<address>
<addrLine>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</addrLine>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>etcenter@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
<availability>
<p>Copyright &#169; 2010 by University of Nebraska, all rights reserved.
Items in the Archive may be shared in accordance with the Fair Use provisions
of U.S. copyright law.  Redistribution or republication on other terms, in
any medium, requires express written consent from the editor and advance
notification of the publisher, the Center for Digital Research in the Humanities.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>

<notesStmt>
<note type="summary">

</note>
</notesStmt>


<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="a">Johnson, Ripple, and Dutch correspondence</title>
<title level="a"></title>
<title level="j">correspondence</title>
<author></author>
<publisher></publisher>
<pubPlace></pubPlace>
<date when="1930-02-16"></date>
<biblScope type="page">unknown</biblScope>
</bibl>
</sourceDesc>

</fileDesc>

<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="water">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="sky">
<term></term>
</keywords>
 <keywords scheme="original" n="land">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="earth">
<term></term>
</keywords>
</textClass>
</profileDesc>

<revisionDesc>
<change when="2010-08-04"><name> Rhiannon Root</name> Proofread</change>
    <change when="2010-06-01"><name>Erin Pedigo</name> Initial Encoding</change>
    <change when="2010"><name>Sam Herley</name> OCR</change>

</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>

<text>

<body>
<div1>

<p>Rapid City, S. Dak.</p>
<p> Mar. 16, 1930.</p>

<p> Mr. O. H. Johnson, Director</p>
<p> Dept. of Game and Fish,</p>
<p> Pierre, S. Dak.</p>

<p> Dear Mr. Johnson:</p>

	<p> Present indications are that Dutch, myself
and possibly one other man will be going to Watertown the 
middle of the coming week, about the twentieth, and as we
have a lot of stuff to take over, includeing two of those
large tanks that are used on the trucks and about sixty or 
more cans, I had planned to use the International truck
that has been here all winter as well as the Ford truck
that has always been here, to haul everything to the Eastern
part of the State all at once, but Dad told me I had better
write you and find out if that would meet with your approval
because he tells me that though he is not sure, he beleives
you said at some time that if you were to sell the large
International, you would want to do so in the West-River
section. Of course the Ford truck will be taken East but 
what Dad told me, leaves me in doubt about the International.</p>

	<p> As I figure, there will be two good truck
loads from here, and then there will be the hauling of the
long twenty-foot staves for the tank at the Pickerel Lake
hatchery, also the pipe to the Byron lake pond, that the
International will prove exceptionally well adapted for.
If you want the large International left here, I wish to
know as soon as I can so that different arrangements can be
made.</p>

	<p> Please have two twenty-five dollar gasoline
coupon books mailed to me immediately as they will be needed
to make the trip, the pick-up taking a different route than
the other trucks.	</p>

	<p> I am writing you about this because Dad is
going direct to Lake Andes before he goes to watertown to
start the spring work there.</p>

		<p>Yours truly,</p> 
<p> R. L. Ripple </p>
</div1>


<div1>

<p> January 13, 1930</p>

<p> Mr. Robert L. Ripple</p>

<p> Rapid City, South Dakota</p> 

<p> Dear Bob:</p>

	<p> I spoke to you at Madison about making a 
talk in Mitchell sometime in January. The
date has been set for the 21st at which time
we are going to present charters to Plankinton,
Mount Vernon, and Alexandria, and we would like
to have you make a good talk similar to that
you made in Madison telling the boys of the 
condition you find in the Lakes Andes and Madison,
and also the plans for the development of the James River.</p>

	<p> Hoping to hear that you will be able to
be with us at that time, I remain as ever,</p>
		

			<p> Yours truly,</p>
		
			<p> L. P. Petersen</p> 

		      <p> President, Izaak walton League</p> 
		
			<p> Mitchell Chapter #43</p> 
</div1>



<div1>

<p> Brookings, S. D.</p> 
<p> Jan. 11, 1930</p> 

<p> Mr. R. J. Ripple</p> 
<p> Lake Andes, S. D.</p> 

<p> Dear Mr. Ripple-</p> 

<p> I was over at Arlington Friday but could not get
in touch with Mr. Smith. I saw his partner Kjelson
and he said that Smith was in Sioux Falls and
that he did not expect him to return to Arlington until
Monday.</p> 

<p> Kjelson thought that Smith had no webbing at Lake 
Brant, but  he was sure that he had some at Lake 
Poinsett. As soon as I can see Smith and find out
whether he has 1200 ft. of bullhead webbing at
Poinsett, we can load it up and start for Lake
Andes if that will hellp you any.
Carl Kjelson was anxious to get started <unclear reason= "illegible"/> at
Lake Hendricks again and he said he intended to
call Mac Randall today (Sat.).</p> 
					<p> Very truly yours</p>
					<p> G. K. Sorenson.</p> 
</div1>


<div1>

<p> 5/15/29.,</p>

<p> Mr. R. W. Ripple, </p>
<p> Rapid City</p>
<p> S. Dak.</p> 

<p> Friend Bob:</p>

	<p> As I have a bunch of foolish ideas and you are about the only
one that I know that would be kind enought to know enough to
answer them. Now if you would be kind enough to let me know what I
would like to know I will try and see that you get a few ducks
or some pheasants next fall.</p> 

	<p> First would it be profitable to try and raise bull heads or
yellow belly cat in a lake that is full of rushes and now has about
four or five feet of water in it. This lake covers about eighty
acres. A person could put in an arteasion well in a few years after
the lake was producing fish enough to pay or big enough to sell.</p> 

	<p> Do you know if the federal department of fisheries has an estimate
on what an acre of water will produce in fish? Or do you know what
it would produce in fish?</p> 

	<p> You see a fellow would not only get more water in the lake in the
winter time with this well but it would all so catch your fish for 
you as they come up in the warm water in the winter time.</p> 

	<p> Do you know where in this state a fellow could get some yellow
belly cat the ones that grow about two or three pounds? How long
would it take to produce a cat of this size under fair water and 
feed conditions? And do you think that it would be profitable to try
bull frogs, or would they grow down here and where would a fellow
get his stock and about what would they cost?</p> 

	<p> Now Bob and I would appreciate it very much if you would answer these
questions for me, and maybe some day I may be able to repay you in some way.</p> 

					<p> Very truly yours,</p> 
				<p>	<unclear reason="signature of Thompson" /> </p>

<p> P.S. Have been catching lots of crappies here in the lake but have 
had no luck with the blue gills but think that they are still 
out in the deep water as I think that the crappie spawns first.</p> 
	
	<p> We are using live bait for the crappies and of coarse do not get
as many blue gill s as if we were using worms.</p> 

	<p> The weather has been very cold down here and do not look for a 
very early fish hatch and that will be that much better as we have
been having a very cold and windy spring.</p> 
</div1>



<div1>

<p> State Fish Hatchery</p>
<p> Pickerel Lake, So. Dakota.</p>

<p> Mr. Merle Thompson,</p>
<p> Lake Andes, South Dakota.</p> 

<p> Dear Mr. Thompson:</p> 

	<p> Received yours of May 15th, here today
and same catches me at a time when I am just about crazy
with work in connection with my Pike Propagation, because
I have so many Pike Fry coming on, its just a dam fine thing
to have to hustle to get them to our different lakes.
Over 7,000,000 little Pike in our tanks at this hatchery
on this date so ou may know I am beside myself in getting
the planting done in a way that will spell success.
Will not go into details in reference to your letter
because you have touched upon TWO propositions that have
merit behind them and both would have to have some real
explanations in order that you can grasp things.</p> 

	<p> I will spend a heap of time in your
territory this summer because success must be made in our
work at that point and the first time I get down there,
will look you up and talk over the matters contained in
your letter and which cannot be explained by leter, owing
to time.         I wish however to say that the Large
Bullfrogs are a coming thing in southern South Dakota.
I have studied them considerable this last year and have
a place in mind where stock can be purchased, down in
Kansas, the address is at Pierre when we would want same.
There is money in frogs if suitable conditions can be had
for such a venture.</p>

	<p> Eighty acres of lake space would handle
a heap of Bullheads but such waters must be of a muddy
nature bottom, plenty of depth the first consideration
and there are many other conditions that must be taken
into consideration.</p>

		<p> Will see you when I get down there.</p> 

	<p>	Very truly yours,</p>
<p> R. L. Ripple </p> 
</div1>


<div1>

<p> July 17/29</p>

<p> Mr. R. L. Ripple</p>
<p> Rapid City, SD</p> 

<p> Dear Mr. Ripple:
Well I arrived here safely
and was glad of it as it certainly
was a hot one. How far did you
get that day. I did not see Ralph
or Harold on my way down here.
Guess they must have forgotten about
getting nets. I suppose after driving
that new Nash home you realize
that I would like to more than 
ever ride in it.</p>

<p> Well now to let you know what
I have been doing since I've been
down here to start in with luck
has been against us. Saturday it
was very windy and couldn't see
anything up in the bay. Sunday it
rained so had to stay in all day.
We went out Monday &amp; Tuesday
but the green algae on the lake
in the North End has been
terribly thick. The wind keeps on
blowing from the South &amp; East.
Today its better and here's hoping
things are cleared up, so that
we can get some Bass. Of course
when we were up there, we 
could get a few by dipping
into the vegetation, but it was
impossible to see any swarms.</p>

<p> The green algae that is on lake
has done quite a bit of damage.
Some of the farmers on North 
side of lake have lost chickens
ducks &amp; turkeys and hogs from
drinking the water out of lake.
One farmer lost ninteen hogs
Another ten. Duffy sent samples
of water to the University to
have analyzed but so far haven't
had a report from it. Well today
things look much brighter
today. Things are in our favor
only its cloudy, but hope that
the green algae is out of the North
end. The nests in pond are no
 more so before going up on lake
we are going on pond to see if
there are any swarms. If, the wind
keeps on like it has from the East
Duffy &amp; I will drive down to Sargent
Lake to see what, we can get down
there. But I'm more interested to
get the Bass out of Lake here.
Well, anyway I'm hoping for the 
best. Well, we are set to go, so
will quit. Will let you know
what luck we had latter part of
week. Regards to folks &amp; the boys.</p> 

<p> With best Personal Wishes.</p>
		<p> Respectfully yours.</p>
		<p> "Dutch."</p>
</div1>


<div1>

<p> Rapid City, July 22, 1929.</p> 

<p> Mr. O. E. Glaseman,</p>
<p> Lake Andes, South Dakota.</p> 

<p> Dear "Dutch":</p> 

	<p> Glad to have your letter July 17th,
telling about the work at Lake Andes.
Sorry to learn the Green Algae has hampered the work
we wished to carry on but it cannot be helped of course.
Only hope you boys have had better luck since your 
letter was mailed to me.</p> 

	<p> Although the work you are now in should
be confined to Lake Andes, it would be well if you have
had the time or will get the time to go down to Sargent
lake to determine th depth of water and other conditions
as how numerous the Black Bass are there.</p>

	<p> I expect to have another letter from you
possibly tomorrow and if it is determined that nothing
worth while can be accomplished there in that special work
I will write you what next to tackle.     At any rate do
not leave there until I write you what you about the next move
because I may have you go into the Winner country and it 
may be you will have to bring through to Rapid City a load
of various sorts or varities of vegetation to go into 
Orman Dam.</p>

	<p> I am sure sorry that algae got so thick 
in the lake there but hope the swarms of young Bass in
the pond are showing up.</p>

	<p> Have been on the rush here ever since coming
home.     Warden Schemmer leaves tonight for his section
with a big load of trout, one load went to State Park this
A. M. and so it goes.</p>

	<p> Give regards to people there and say "Hello" 
to "Duffy."</p> 

				   <p> Yours,</p> 
     <p> R. L. Ripple</p>
</div1>



<div1>

				<p> Lake Andes, S. D.</p> 
				<p> July 24/29</p>

<p> Mr. R. L. Ripple</p>
<p> Rapid City, S. D.</p>

<p> Dear Mr. Ripple:</p>

		<p> Received your letter today
and very glad to hear. Well, things have
quieted down considerably this past
week, so far we have taken about
2500 young Bass out of Lake, but the
Green Algae is still in the North End 
of Lake. These Bass that we got were
all in small bunches and very
hard to get. I really believe that the
large swarms have all broken
up. Not more than twenty or thirty
in a bunch and a lot of bunches
with only six and seven in them.</p>

<p> I don't believe that it would pay
to really try to get anymore as 
it takes all day long just to get
four or five hundred. Duffy sure 
was disgusted to think that we
couldn't run across any large
swarms. He wasn't any more
disgusted than I, as <unclear reason="illegible" />
was looking forward to getting quite
a few. I really think that if the
Green Algae and the wind hadn't been
we most likely would have gotten
quite a few. Just our luck to have
this happen. Well, about Sargent's
Lake, last Thursday, the wind blew
so hard we couldn't see anything
on Lake in a. m. so Duffy &amp; I decided
to go down there. I really don't see
any lake part about it. </p>

<p> It is the old river bottom but is cut off
from River until high waters in
spring. We spent about five hours
there. The average depth is about
five feet some vegetation and its all
mud bottom. Nothing but Bullheads 
and very few shiners &amp; Sun Fish but no
Bass.</p>
 
 <p>We talked to quite a few
farmers that live around there
and very few fish in it. They
most likely would if there
were any fish in it <unclear reason="illegible" /> never
goes dry but gets shallow. The 
widest part I don't believe is over a hundred feet. I should judge
that it isn't over six or seven
miles long and dry in parts where
around or lay of land runs
higher. Well, we are still at it
hard to get more Bass for pond;
so shall stay right here until
I hear from you again. Should have
written before I received your
letter, but sure was glad to
hear and shall do my very
best to accomplish more than
what we have under these conditions that have been in the lake.
I gave your regards to Duffy and rest. 
He also sends them best regards 
to you folks. Also regards to
folks from me &amp; Here's to boys hoping
to hear soon. I am as usual,
With Best Personal Wishes.</p> 
	
		           <p>Respectfully Yours,</p> 
			               <p>"Dutch."</p> 
</div1>

</body>
</text>
</TEI>                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                             