<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.2.0/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="cdn.land.resort.0022">
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title level="m" type="main">Bass in the Lake Acting Very Peculiar</title>
<title level="m" type="sub"></title>
<principal n="Nesheim, David A.">David Nesheim</principal>
</titleStmt>

<editionStmt>
<edition><date>2012</date></edition>
</editionStmt>
<publicationStmt>
<idno>cdn.water.boat.0020</idno>
 <authority>Casting Digital Nets: Fishery Modeling, Native Dispossession, and Dynamic History on the Great Plains</authority>
<distributor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln Libraries</distributor>
<address>
<addrLine>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</addrLine>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
<availability>
<p>Copyright &#169; 2012 by University of Nebraska, all rights reserved.
Items in the Archive may be shared in accordance with the Fair Use provisions
of U.S. copyright law.  Redistribution or republication on other terms, in
any medium, requires express written consent from the editor and advance
notification of the publisher, the Center for Digital Research in the Humanities.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>

<notesStmt>
<note type="summary">

</note>
</notesStmt>


<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="a" type="original">Untitled</title>
<title level="a" type="supplied">Bass in the Lake Acting Very Peculiar</title>
<title level="j">Spencer News</title>
<author></author>
<publisher></publisher>
<pubPlace></pubPlace>
<date when="1914-06-11"></date>
<biblScope type="page">4</biblScope>
</bibl>
</sourceDesc>

</fileDesc>

<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="water">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="sky">
<term></term>
</keywords>
 <keywords scheme="original" n="land">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="earth">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="keyword">
<term></term>
</keywords>
</textClass>
</profileDesc>

<revisionDesc>
    <change when="2012-11-14"><name>Laura Weakly</name> Fixed title</change>
    <change when="2010-02-18"><name>Laura Weakly</name> Initial Encoding</change>
    <change when="2010"><name>Sam Herley</name> OCR</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>

<text>


<body>

<head type="main"></head>
<head type="sub"></head>

<p>Kimball Graphic: The Lake Andes Wave remarks that the bass in the lake act very peculiar this season for some
reason or other. And it is even so. Fact is, they always do. When they do not something evidently is wrong with
them. The man who thinks he knows all about the habits of black bass doesn't know the first thing about
the critters. The more experienced the angler the less he claims to know. The best of them can't select a 
good fishing day and deliver the goods more than once in times to bat. One day the bass will strike at anything
within striking distance, and you'll reel in nine out of ten that strike. The next day or the day after, or the day 
after that, with exactly the same temperature, wind and weather conditions, you won't get a strike &#8212; or if you do, you can't
hook them. Moreover, much of this talk about the bass taking one bait one day and another kind another day is
moonshine when applied to the big mouth variety. When they are striking freely one bait is as good as another
if not better.</p>

<p>The town has been full of strangers this week, who are enjoying the fishing at the lake. And the fishing
has been pretty good, in fact, better than for the past two or three weeks. as a consequence everyone was
well supplied with fish.</p>

</body>
</text>
</TEI>