<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.2.0/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="cdn.land.letter.0002">
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title level="m" type="main">Ripple carp correspondence</title>
<title level="m" type="sub"></title>
<principal>David Nesheim</principal>
</titleStmt>

<editionStmt>
<edition><date>2010</date></edition>
</editionStmt>
<publicationStmt>
<idno>cdn.land.letter.0002</idno>
 <authority>Casting Digital Nets: Fishery Modeling, Native Dispossession, and Dynamic History on the Great Plains</authority>
<distributor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln Libraries</distributor>
<address>
<addrLine>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</addrLine>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>etcenter@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
<availability>
<p>Copyright &#169; 2010 by University of Nebraska, all rights reserved.
Items in the Archive may be shared in accordance with the Fair Use provisions
of U.S. copyright law.  Redistribution or republication on other terms, in
any medium, requires express written consent from the editor and advance
notification of the publisher, the Center for Digital Research in the Humanities.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>

<notesStmt>
<note type="summary">

</note>
</notesStmt>


<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="a">Ripple carp correspondence</title>
<title level="a"></title>
<title level="j">correspondence</title>
<author></author>
<publisher></publisher>
<pubPlace></pubPlace>
<date when="1936-02-07"></date>
<biblScope type="page">unknown</biblScope>
</bibl>
</sourceDesc>

</fileDesc>

<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="water">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="sky">
<term></term>
</keywords>
 <keywords scheme="original" n="land">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="earth">
<term></term>
</keywords>
</textClass>
</profileDesc>

<revisionDesc>
<change when="2010-08-04"><name> Rhiannon Root</name> Proofread</change>
    <change when="2010-06-01"><name>Erin Pedigo</name> Initial Encoding</change>
    <change when="2010"><name>Sam Herley</name> OCR</change>

</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>

<text>

<body>
<div1>


<p> Watertown, February 7, 1936.

 Mr. O. H. Johnson, Director,
 Department of Game and Fish,
 Pierre, South Dakota.</p>

<p> Dear Mr. Johnson:</p>

	<p> No doubt you have some times thought about
the carp that we have cribbed ever since the start of
our operations at Kampeska lake along with other carp that we
contacted from time to time.    Well Brushaber always as usual
was waiting until we had a carload and did not want to ship
dead shiptments <sic>shipments</sic> so we held onto them with tender handling etc.</p>

	<p> The terrific weather came and operations were held up, the carp were getting old and I getting scared so a call came from old Sam Flax of Omaha for carp and buffalo fish.
Knowing Sam as I do, I knew he would be out for cheap fish as
usual but I advised him he better come along and size up what
we had on hand.</p>

	<p> Letters from the eastern buyers, telephone
calls, suggestions from Brushaber relative to his prices on
carp and the whole kaboodle told me that all we could expect
from any and all sources would be 4 cts. per pound on carp.</p>

	<p>Sam Flax came on and to make a long story short,
I got 4 cts. per pound from him for 4,800# of the oldest cribbed
carp and 6 1/2 cts. per pound for about 800# of buffalo fish.
Will mail in the report covering this shortly.
The Flax truck carried new knocked-down boxes which I helped
him put together and which fact made me wonder a little for
going onto the Omaha market.    Casually looking about I learn
that this total bunch of boxed carp were later shipped from
Arlington, to some point in Canada. Eastern Canada.
The buffalo were no doubt taken back to Omaha.</p>

	<p> Off hand, without looking up our records of
fish cribbed, I think we have between 2 and 3 thousand pounds
of later caught carp cribbed that are in good shape.
I was relieved when those carp went and if no better prospect
shows up in the near future, I may again sound out Flax.
It may be the jews <sic>Jews</sic> are leaving Germany for Canada, at any rate
I get a big kick out of the whole darn thing when it comes
to CARP MARKETS.   The eastern buyers are still bossing the
job and making good at it.</p> 

				<p> Very truly yours,</p> 
         <p>R. L. Ripple</p> 

</div1>


<div1>

<p> Watertown, April 4, 1936.

Mr. O. H. Johnson, Director,
Department of Game and Fish,
Pierre, South Dakota.</p>

<p> Dear Mr. Johnson:

	Referring to your letter April 2nd,
also copy of letter to Mr. W. H. Dent, President, Aberdeen
Chapter I. W. L. A. relative to obtaining stock fish from
the few remaining natural lakes with which to stock the
new dams in the vicinity of Aberdeen.</p>

	<p> In my opinion you have so thoroughly
covered the matter of stocking our new artificial lakes
in so far as our fish resources go or are in evidence
at the present time there remains little if any room
for further comment.</p> 

	<p> When the ice bound shores of our few
remaining lakes in the north eastern part of the state
again splash out into waves of open water, we find that
the past terrible winter conditions have not been to harsh
on the fish-life contained in them, we should be mighty happy,
however, in no mood to carry on a program that would take from
them adult game fish for the re-stocking of artificial lakes 
in the face of the fact that our department has very well taken care
of the latter through a wise, sane, re-stocking program that
we know will give hook and line fishing at the earliest possible
time consistent with the conditions of new waters that are not
as conducive to the well fare of many varieties in their new
state as natural lakes that are retaining their water supply.</p>

	<p> Personally I have no sympathy with those who
would tear down the program of the department that has the 
experience in fisheries work and the matter of hook and line
flshing at heart, with its life blood, and go over to a hap-
hazzard program that can have but one ending, dissatisfaction.</p> 

	<p> This, that and the other, could be added to
your letter explaining at length the requirements of fish in
newly constructed waters, in fact a treatise could be written
a half mile long but your letter is full of meat, there is
no call for anything of the kind.</p> 
</div1>

<div1>

<p> Mr. O. H. Johnson 2,

	You know fully well that going to look
at a new lake recently filled or partly filled with water
is to the layman a wonderful sight just as it is to us,
however, the layman at once comes to the conclusion that it 
should harbor about all these different varieties of fish
native to the very natural state waters and in that conclusion he
is so very far from right that it is  very hard to convince him
when our first load of young stock fish arrive on the sceen,
that another load should not be at once on the way so that
hook and line fishing can be started about the first of next
week.</p> 

	<p> I am thinking of Lake Andes, Lake Campell and 
perhaps other natural lakes that have or may get their water back
this spring. I am thinking of those great spawning areas that 
will again be intact for adult spawning fish when the re-production
would be great if only the adults were on hand. Then why should
we think of supplying adult game fish adults as breeders for
artificial waters that are in their infancy with little or no
opportunity for adult fish to propagate. Wouldn't I like to
just have a few thousand adult northern pike, black bass and the 
like for breeders in the lakes I mention in this paragraph, but
I am loath to go into any natural lake even to that extent.</p> 

	<p> It is my opinion that during the past year our
department put over one of the greatest re-stocking programs ever
attempted by any state in the union and another such program is 
in the making for this season.   Fish planted by experienced men,
not by application and dumped by laymen who know as little about
the planting fish and their requirements as they do about proper
varieties, lake conditions etc.   We have in this state a few
sample dams that got away from us in the matter of Tom, Dick and 
Harry stocking the fish, that will suffer for many years.
On the other hand we have those new waters that have their governing
according to our program that are producing that for which they
were constructed in the matter of fishing.</p> 
</div1>


<div1>

<p> Mr. O. H. Johnson 3,
	The Aberdeen territory being thickly populated
and inhabited by a wonderful bunch of sports people whom have
not been accustomed to easy access to nearby fishing waters like
some of the larger city areas, are overly anxious to the time
hook and line fishing can start in their dams and for that they
cannot be blamed, however, it is hoped that they can see fit to
abide with a program that will with the display of a little
patitence, give them ore and better fishing recreation that
all the hap-hazzard work they could accomplish otherwise.</p> 

	<p> Hundreds of thousands of wall-eyed pike,
thousands of fine black bass fingerlings, also bullheads of
various sizes and nature slowly but surely making conditions all
set and so if the dams retain what water they have or more comes
to them, along with perhaps additional stock fish from the Jim
River and from our hatcheries, what more can be asked?</p> 

	<p> Even if a program was put over allowing the 
holder of a fishing license to retain his fish bag limit in
a live state with the intention to use for stocking some new
waters, it would cause a great amount of confusion and not the 
proper opportunity to know what was going on as to varieties
being handled etc.</p>
	
			 <p>  Very truly yours,</p> 
       <p> R. L. Ripple</p> 
</div1>


<div1>

               <p>April 2, 1936

Mr. W. H. Dent, President
Aberdeen Chapter I. W. L. A.
Aberdeen, South Dakota</p> 

<p> Dear Mr. Dent:

	This will acknowledge receipt of your letter of
March 31st and while we sincerely appreciate the interest
which your organization is taking in the prompt and adequate
stocking with suitable fish, of new waters in Brown County,
we cannot, without subjecting ourselves to severe criticisms,
authorize your organization to take stock from natural lakes
for introduction into your lakes.</p>

	<p> We do, however, believe that a vast supply of de-
sirable game fish will be available from the waters of the 
James River throughout this season and we assure you that
no effort will be spared by our wardens in these rescue
operations and that in the distribution of the fish thus res-
cued, all lakes suitable for the reception of stock will be
supplied. Our wardens have been instructed to avoid placing
valuable stocks of fish in lakes that do not have sufficient
depth to insure their protection and inasmuch as Mina and 
Richmond lakes are gradually filling up in spite of sub-normal
precipitation, we feel justified in continuing stocking operations
consistent with the natural food supply in those bodies of water.</p> 

	<p> There is, you will understand, danger of over-
stocking lakes, as all fish in order to thrive must have an
ample supply of natural food. This supply consists not only
of food minnows of of lower forms of animal life that has
its origin in acquatic plant life. Until a lake has reached
its maximum water level, an intelligent progress of plant in-
troduction cannot be undertaken.</p> 

	<p> With this in mind we hope that your group will
assist us in carrying out tested stocking policies and thus
avoid, so far as is humanly possible, unnecessary waste of
valuable foundation stock, which might result should our
stocking operations progress more rapidly than conditions
warrant.</p> 
</div1>


<div1>

<p> W. H. D.

	We hardly regard the introduction of breeders into
these new lakes essential, inasmuch as natural spawning habitat
for other than bullheads and black bass, is not present.
Better results we know will be obtained by the transfer of
game fish hatched in natural environment.</p>

	<p> Much as we would like to introduce adult fish into
our new lakes in sufficient numbers so that immediate angling
might be available, this I believe you will agree is
physically impossible. I do believe that by July 1937,
fishing under restrictive regulations might reasonably be
expected in Elna Dam. Nothing creates more interest and
enthusiasm for an artificial lake than do fishing privileges
and as a means of stimulating interest in these projects,
the Commission feels justified in permitting limited fishing
as promptly as possible. This policy I believe will appeal 
to your organization and we pledge our best efforts to the
end that this ambition may be realized.

			      Very truly yours,


OHJ: AW		<milestone unit="absent" />, Director,
			Department of Game and Fish.</p> 
</div1>


<div1>

<p> Watertown, April 6, 1936.

Mr. Walter B. Neville,,
Clear Lake, South Dakota.</p>

<p> Dear Sir:

	Referring to your letter April 3rd, asking
for information relative to game and fish management
and what is being done in this state wether or not
a college education would be necessary in order to
acquire a position in such work.</p> 

	<p> Will say that a college education is of course
a wonderful asset to attain for the following of any
line of endeavor including game and fisheries management
however perhaps it is not entirely necessary.</p> 

	<p> So far as our fisheries  department is concerned
at the present time we have several of our old employes
off duty due to the past couple seasons of drought when
some of the work was curtailed owing to drying up of lakes
etc.    There is nothing I could suggest at this time in
the way of a position in the fisheries department.</p> 

	<p> In reference to your request for pamphlets or other
bulletins pertaining to game and fish in connection with
our department I would suggest that you drop a line to
the Department of Game and Fish, Pierre, S. D. asking for
such pamphlets as they may have something of interest to help you in
your quest for information relative same.</p> 

	<p> Personally I appreicate very much your interest in
the work I have followed most of my life and I am going to
make it a point to call on you at Clear Lake the very first
time I get that way when we can talk over the things that 
would interest you in the conservation of game and fish.

				Very truly yours,
                       Department of Game and Fish
		
				<milestone unit="absent" />
				Supt. of Fisheries,
				R. L. Ripple, Watertown, S. D. </p> 
</div1>


<div1>

<p> April 7, 1936


R. L. Ripple, Supt. of Fisheries
c/o Kampeska Hotel
Watertown, S. Dak.</p> 

<p> Dear Bob
	
This will acknowledge receipt of your letter of April 4th
and appreciate your comment on my letter to W. H. Dent,
President of the Aberdeen Chapter of the I. W. L. A. It is
quite evident that the Aberdeen enthusiasts will have to have
their "sights lowered" considerably. They seem to proceed
on the theory that this Department has no other responsibilities
than that of stocking new waters in Brown County. I can appre-
ciate their enthusiam and only wish there were more communities
in the state similarly afflicted. However, our job is to
serve the entire state and we can ill afford to neglect a com-
munity because they do not resort to strong-arm methods in
getting what they want. I am confident that by a year from 
next July anglers will be taking good fish from the waters of
Mina Lake. When that time arrives we will have less trouble
getting along with sportsmen in that section.</p> 

				   <p> Very truly yours
		   		O. H. Johnson ,Director
				 Department of Game and Fish</p> 

<p> OHJ:CC</p> 
</div1>

</body>
</text>
</TEI>

			
