<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.2.0/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="cdn.land.letter.0007">
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title level="m" type="main">A. G. McBride correspondence</title>
<title level="m" type="sub"></title>
<principal>David Nesheim</principal>
</titleStmt>

<editionStmt>
<edition><date>2010</date></edition>
</editionStmt>
<publicationStmt>
<idno>cdn.land.letter.0007</idno>
 <authority>Casting Digital Nets: Fishery Modeling, Native Dispossession, and Dynamic History on the Great Plains</authority>
<distributor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln Libraries</distributor>
<address>
<addrLine>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</addrLine>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>etcenter@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
<availability>
<p>Copyright &#169; 2010 by University of Nebraska, all rights reserved.
Items in the Archive may be shared in accordance with the Fair Use provisions
of U.S. copyright law.  Redistribution or republication on other terms, in
any medium, requires express written consent from the editor and advance
notification of the publisher, the Center for Digital Research in the Humanities.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>

<notesStmt>
<note type="summary">

</note>
</notesStmt>


<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="a">A. G. McBride correspondence</title>
<title level="a"></title>
<title level="j">correspondence</title>
<author></author>
<publisher></publisher>
<pubPlace></pubPlace>
<date when="1930-03-09"></date>
<biblScope type="page">unknown</biblScope>
</bibl>
</sourceDesc>

</fileDesc>

<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="water">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="sky">
<term></term>
</keywords>
 <keywords scheme="original" n="land">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="earth">
<term></term>
</keywords>
</textClass>
</profileDesc>

<revisionDesc>
<change when="2010-08-05"><name> Rhiannon Root</name> Proofread</change>
    <change when="2010-06-01"><name>Erin Pedigo</name> Initial Encoding</change>
    <change when="2010"><name>Sam Herley</name> OCR</change>

</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>

<text>

<body>
<div1>

				<p> Rapid City, March 9, 1930.</p>

<p> Mr. A. G. McBride, Commissioner,
Department of Game &amp; Fish,
Lake Andes, South Dakota.</p>

<p> Dear Mr. McBride:</p>

	<p> I got in touch with Duffy Algar <sic>Allgier</sic> and find
that the seining crew has not to date shown up at Lake
Andes and presume from present indications that they may
not get down there until just as the ice is or has gone
out of the north end of the lake.    Duffy said he was
getting in touch with some-one <sic> someone</sic> connected with the seining
work and taht as I understood him to say, he had talked 
or heard from "Moose" Randal.</p>

	<p>The sum and substance of the letter enclosed,
copy of letter sent to Duffy today, I talked over with him
on the phone, station to station call at $.75 so the expense
was not great and I wanted to be sure whether or not they were
seining at this time down there.</p>

	<p>I am making an effert <sic>effort</sic> to get in touch by mail
with Mr. Randal in order to be sure that things will terminate
in the proper manner at Lake Andes this spring in reference
to the Carp        Some part of the Randal outfit is just
starting operations again at Hendricks lake from a word I
got from my supervisor there, so will trace "Moose" from there
since I believe his borther <sic>brother</sic> is the one operating at Hendricks
at this time.</p>

	<p>Had some difficulty getting through to Rapid
owing to that big storm out Midland way but plows etc. were
rapidly getting the road in shape.</p>

				<p>  truly yours,</p>
				<p> . Ripple</p>
</div1>

<div1>

			<p> Rapid City, March 9, 1930.</p>

<p> Mr. "Duffy" Algar,
Lake Andes, South Dakota.</p>


            <p> Dear Mr. Algar:</p>
	
<p> Carp.</p>       

   <p> In line with our talk over the phone
today, Mr. McBride told me at the Pierre meeting that 
he understood the seiners would be down there ready to
start operations at this time.     Mr. Randal phoned me
a couple weeks ago that he had a man down there watching
conditions for the spring seining and that just as soon
as conditions were right that the crew would be on hand 
to again try for Carp.</p>

	<p> As I understand conditions, the smallest freshet
came early this spring and so far as this freshet is concerned,
the crew was not there to work under the ice.
However we must deal with present and the near future
conditions and I know as well as Mr. Randal that little can
be gained by trying to seine under the ice the while the
soft weather of early spring will put water on the ice and 
otherwise make conditions for working on the ice anything
but satisfactory or safe.</p>

	<p> If the warm weather continues until the
break-up, I cannot see how much can be accomplished until we
can seine in open water at the north end of the lake where
the remaining  Carp that have been attracted by the fresh waters
will remain until such open water seining is attempted.
So speaking, I am at the mercy of the Randals to be on hand
for such open water fishing since they have promised me all
winter that they would do the work of spring Carp fishing down
there.</p>

<p> Bass.</p>  

	<p> Referring to our conversation in reference to
the Bass pond etc.     The bottom of the new pond should be
burned off or mowed off if it is not dry enough to burn and
the bottom if it can be arranged, plowed up and dragged or
leveled off so we can later in the season, plant water vegetation.
We will have a heap of green algae or green slime as it is
commonly called, in that new pond the coming summer in any
case and as is always the case in the flooding of water over
land the first year, but we will have less of the nuisance if 
we can plow up the bottom and turn under the land grasses and
weeds.     There will be no reason to hurry the filling of
the new pond with water since that can be done much later on.</p> 
</div1>

<div1>

<p> Mr. Algar  <sic>Allgier</sic> . . . 2,</p>

	<p> We should make every effort to obtain breeding Bass from
the seining operations or otherwise in order to get the parent
Bass from the lake as soon after the ice goes out as possible,
the breeders thus gotten for use in the new pond this season.
Any breeders taken this spring can be placed in the lower or
old pond until we drain that pond down to sort what breeders
for males and females that we have there.</p>

	 <p> It is my opinion that possibly we will have better results
in the nesting and hatching of Bass in our new pond this year
that in that old pond for various reasons and especially so
if we can arrange to get the bottom of  the new pond burned off
or mowed off and plowed and leveled up over the area of the
bottom that is not under water at the present time.
The area of the new pond that is at present under water at the
center over the lower part of same and covered with cat-tails
will not be harmfull <sic>harmful</sic> as it is for it will affort cover for
young fish and is water vegetation in itself.</p>
	
	<p> Personally, I have considerable work out here in connection with
some new road grading at the hatchery and numerous other details
to look after previous to turning east for the spring work at
the Pike hatcheries, Bass hatcheries and the rough fish work 
at various places so kindly keep me informed in reference to
when anything is attempted in seining at Andes
As you say, you can arrange to look after any seine hauls and
getting the new pond in condition until such time as I can
go from here to Andes and then to my other eastern work.</p> 

			 <closer><salute> Very truly yours,</salute>
			<signed> Department of Game &amp; Fish,
			R. L. Ripple
			Supt. of Fisheries,
			R. L. Ripple.</signed></closer>
</div1>

</body>
</text>
</TEI>

