<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.2.0/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="cdn.land.resort.0002">
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title level="m" type="main">Parker Stops at Limit</title>
<title level="m" type="sub"></title>
<principal n="Nesheim, David A.">David Nesheim</principal>
</titleStmt>
<editionStmt>
<edition><date>2012</date></edition>
</editionStmt>
<publicationStmt>
<idno>cdn.water.boat.0020</idno>
 <authority>Casting Digital Nets: Fishery Modeling, Native Dispossession, and Dynamic History on the Great Plains</authority>
<distributor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln Libraries</distributor>
<address>
<addrLine>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</addrLine>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
<availability>
<p>Copyright &#169; 2012 by University of Nebraska, all rights reserved.
Items in the Archive may be shared in accordance with the Fair Use provisions
of U.S. copyright law.  Redistribution or republication on other terms, in
any medium, requires express written consent from the editor and advance
notification of the publisher, the Center for Digital Research in the Humanities.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>

<notesStmt>
<note type="summary">

</note>
</notesStmt>


<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="a">Untitled</title>
<title level="a">Parker Stops at Limit</title>
<title level="j">Spencer News</title>
<author></author>
<publisher></publisher>
<pubPlace></pubPlace>
<date when="1905-08-31"></date>
<biblScope type="page"></biblScope>
</bibl>
</sourceDesc>

</fileDesc>

<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="water">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="sky">
<term></term>
</keywords>
 <keywords scheme="original" n="land">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="earth">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="keyword">
<term></term>
</keywords>
</textClass>
</profileDesc>

<revisionDesc>
    <change when="2012-11-14"><name>Laura Weakly</name> Supplied title</change>
    <change when="2010-02-18"><name>Laura Weakly</name> Initial Encoding</change>
    <change when="2010-01-25"><name>Sam Herley</name> OCR</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>

<text>


<body>

<p>Ralph Parker with his new gun and his eagle eye stopped at the limit
of the game law and left a couple of prairie chickens for the 
newspaper family.</p>
   <p>A. Amundson and Robert Craig went to Platte Tuesday evening on 
business, and while they were on the return train concluded to go to
Chamberlain to see the new sights here.</p>
   <p>Two seperator outfits have been landed by A. Amundson and C.W. 
Rathbun, the traveling salesman of the Avery people. No other town
on this line can compare in any way with this infant burg, and 
particularly in machinery sales of the two firms here.</p>
   <p>Rev. E.H. Grant, Sunday school superintendant of the state, was 
the guest of Rev. Berry and other friends several days this week
and will remain over Sunday and preach instead of Rev. McClement of
Platte, who was to have exchanged pulpits with Mr. Berry, but his 
hay fever was not in the least generous to him.</p>
   <p>Mesdeames Adam Grimes and John Absher and Misses Minnie Absher 
and Dora Amundson came up from Wagner Monday evening and were guests
of the Amundson home. The former returned next day and left the 
young ladies to enjoy the tastes of combination city and resort life.
Miss Alma Heligas, a teacher in the Tyndal schools, joined them 
Wednesday.</p>  
   <p>H.G. Harris, representing the Sioux Falls Daily Press, was in town
Tuesday and wrote up a glowing description of Lake Andes, its 
agricultural surroundings and hunting, fishing, and resort features,
aided by photos of the town. He has been joined by J.N. Harris, D.C.
Ricker, and Los Mulvey of his home city, and together they will
assist in opening the game season.</p>


</body>
</text>
</TEI>