<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.2.0/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="cdn.land.letter.0005">
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title level="m" type="main">Johnson, Ripple, and Dutch correspondence</title>
<title level="m" type="sub"></title>
<principal>David Nesheim</principal>
</titleStmt>

<editionStmt>
<edition><date>2010</date></edition>
</editionStmt>
<publicationStmt>
<idno>cdn.land.letter.0005</idno>
 <authority>Casting Digital Nets: Fishery Modeling, Native Dispossession, and Dynamic History on the Great Plains</authority>
<distributor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln Libraries</distributor>
<address>
<addrLine>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</addrLine>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>etcenter@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
<availability>
<p>Copyright &#169; 2010 by University of Nebraska, all rights reserved.
Items in the Archive may be shared in accordance with the Fair Use provisions
of U.S. copyright law.  Redistribution or republication on other terms, in
any medium, requires express written consent from the editor and advance
notification of the publisher, the Center for Digital Research in the Humanities.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>

<notesStmt>
<note type="summary">

</note>
</notesStmt>


<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="a">Karl Mundt correspondence</title>
<title level="a"></title>
<title level="j">correspondence</title>
<author></author>
<publisher></publisher>
<pubPlace></pubPlace>
<date when="1930-02-16"></date>
<biblScope type="page">unknown</biblScope>
</bibl>
</sourceDesc>

</fileDesc>

<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="water">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="sky">
<term></term>
</keywords>
 <keywords scheme="original" n="land">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="earth">
<term></term>
</keywords>
</textClass>
</profileDesc>

<revisionDesc>
<change when="2010-08-04"><name> Rhiannon Root</name> Proofread</change>
    <change when="2010-06-01"><name>Erin Pedigo</name> Initial Encoding</change>
    <change when="2010"><name>Sam Herley</name> OCR</change>

</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>

<text>

<body>
<div1>


<p> June 3, 1933.</p>

<p> Dear Bob:</p>

	<p> As program chairman for the state Izaak Walton
League Convention, I have put you down for a 15 minute
talk on "Future Fishing Conditions in South Dakota".
Please prepare the best talk of your young life and give
the boys something to remember and something to look forward
to. Your talk will come Monday, June 19.   Due to the
fact we have just a one-day convention, this year, we are
asking the boys to adhere strictly to their time limits
and we are going for Shorter and Better Speeches.</p>

	<p> Please let me have your confirmation of this
speech assignment as soon as possible.</p> 

	<p> I hope fishing operations are going along fine,
Bob, and there are just two things we'd like down here
before Convention time which would do a lot for Bob
Ripple's popularity and a lot for Lake County Lakes:</p>

	<p> (1) We should have some more Pike fry for Lake
Herman. We got some nice fry, Bob, but not very many of
them as we put some of them in Lake Badus. Can't you send
us a few more for Herman??</p>

	<p> (2) You have long promised us some more BASS for
Herman and Badus but they have never been forthcoming.
You were going to get them from the ponds at Lake Andes
or from some salvage work along the river. What has
happened in this regard? Can't you locate us some bass,
adults or fingerlings, and send them down before the 18th?</p>

	<p> Best wishes.</p>
		
					<p> Cordially yours,</p>
					  <p> Karl. E. Mundt.</p>
</div1>


<div1>

	<p> Watertown, June 6, 1933.</p>

<p> Mr. Karl E. Mundt, Vice Chairman,
Department of Game and Fish,
Madison, South Dakota.</p>

<p> Dear Mr. Mundt,</p>
	
	<p>A million thanks for the opportunity
extended in your letter June 3rd, to talk about fish
and fishing for 15 minutes at the coming convention in
the Izaak Walton League at Madison Monday, June 19th,
and I will endeavor to plan my work so that nothing will
stand in the way for me to attend so far as possible.
We have put over a big program this spring in fisheries
work and have now turned to getting rough fish from the 
Sioux River above and at the Flandreau Dam where people
were getting quite sour to have something done.
With my short crew combined with so many things to look
after at this particular season its rather difficult to
cover it all but Karl I am out to endeavor to show those
people at Flandreau that we will co-operate with them
and so my men and self are making an effort that I hope
will be a success and ask that you back me in this endeavor.</p>

	<p> About the wall-eyed pike fry, you did not
get so very many cans but you did get a wonderful number
and quality of fry in them since that trip was a short one
from our hatchery so I could pile them in thick.
I wont say anything about the planting of pike fry in Badus
lake instead of placing them all in Lake Herman however
they may do well at Badus.     Those pike fry were nearly two
weeks old and of very fine quality and just a couple days after
that shiptment was sent forth along with others, our hatchery
was closed up for the season.    I have had no end of letters
from people around our lakes like Big Stone etc. telling of
their appreication for the wonderful plants of pike this year.</p>

	<p> Those breeder black bass I spoke of sending to
Lake Herman this spring could not be had as I learned from
E. E. Allgier, Lake Andes. Duffy first told me he would
get them down there however later he told me he did not have
them to send so thats all I know about this deal.
During our work this spring I havent been in position to get
any bass breeders even for our state ponds although we have
a good supply left over from former years that will fill the
bill. Although I am extremely sorry the Lake Andes bass
did not terminate for Lake Herman there is nothing I can do
at this time.</p> 
</div1>


<div1>

<p> Mr. Karl Mundt . . . 2</p> 

	<p> When the man went to Madison with pike fry
I told him to let you know that Duffy had said he did not
have the bass breeders to send and again when I met warden
Cliff Coffey here at Watertown I told him to let you know.
Although I am not passing the goat to Duffy, I had depended
on him to get you these bass after he told me he would.</p>

	<p> I am planning out a new program at our
Redfield bass hatchery this summer to create an output of
large bass fingerlings this fall season that will put that
place on the may in a big way and from a letter received from
Liebig last night it looks as though this program will bear
fruit to the extent that everyone will set up and take notice.
I wont brag to much now but the propagation of black bass
fingerlings will have its day this fall at that hatchery.
The supposed lowly bullhead will also have its day there.</p>

	<p> With my total crew and self tied up with the 
Flandreau work of getting out rough fish above that dam I
wont have any opportunity to get further fish to Madison
previous to the coming meeting however may you realize that
to me it is very plain what the people want in more and better
fishing in that locality and its ever in my mind to do all
possible to that end.</p>

	<p> While we were on the pike work at the Kampeska
hatchery, Mr. Coffee asked me for some perch for Lake Herman
saying there was such a demand for same and although possibly
it is not just proper to start perch in there with the pike,
I did send down about 1,100 good sized perch for Herman.</p>
				
				<p> Again thanking you for the invitation Mr. Mundt,
					Cordially yours,
					R. L. Ripple</p>
</div1>



<div1>

<p> Watertown, June 27, 1933.</p>

<p> New Bedford Cordage Co.
230 West Huron Street,
Chicago, Illinois.</p> 

<p> Gentlemen:

	Replying to yours June 23rd, asking for
list of commercial fishermen in South Dakota, will
give the following names and addresses.</p> 

		<p> Chas. Smith       Arlington, S. D.
            W. W. Williams    Watertown, S. D.
            K. J. Kjellsen    Arlington, S. D.   Garage
            Jerry Wilson      Sisseton, S. D.    Pool Hall 
            Dick Allen,  % Jerry Wilson, Sisseton, S. D.
            Joe Kiner,        Lake Norden, S. D.
            Chas. Nitteberg,  Castlewood or Estelline, S. D.</p> 

		<p> The above seven names are about all the commerical
fishermen who have been engaged in such work in South Dakota
during recent years.</p> 

                   <p> Very truly yours,
                   Department of Game and Fish,
                      R. L. Ripple
                    Supt. of  Fisheries,
                    R. L. Ripple</p>
</div1>

</body>
</text>
</TEI>
