<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.2.0/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="cdn.land.resort.0023">
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title level="m" type="main">Private fish ponds</title>
<title level="m" type="sub"></title>
<principal n="Nesheim, David A.">David Nesheim</principal>
</titleStmt>

<editionStmt>
<edition><date>2012</date></edition>
</editionStmt>
<publicationStmt>
<idno>cdn.water.boat.0020</idno>
 <authority>Casting Digital Nets: Fishery Modeling, Native Dispossession, and Dynamic History on the Great Plains</authority>
<distributor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln Libraries</distributor>
<address>
<addrLine>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</addrLine>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
<availability>
<p>Copyright &#169; 2012 by University of Nebraska, all rights reserved.
Items in the Archive may be shared in accordance with the Fair Use provisions
of U.S. copyright law.  Redistribution or republication on other terms, in
any medium, requires express written consent from the editor and advance
notification of the publisher, the Center for Digital Research in the Humanities.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>

<notesStmt>
<note type="summary">

</note>
</notesStmt>


<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="a" type="original">Private fish ponds</title>
<title level="a"></title>
<title level="j">Spencer News</title>
<author></author>
<publisher></publisher>
<pubPlace></pubPlace>
<date when="1914-05-21"></date>
<biblScope type="page">1</biblScope>
</bibl>
</sourceDesc>

</fileDesc>

<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="water">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="sky">
<term></term>
</keywords>
 <keywords scheme="original" n="land">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="earth">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="keyword">
<term></term>
</keywords>
</textClass>
</profileDesc>

<revisionDesc>
    <change when="2012-11-14"><name>Laura Weakly</name> Fixed title</change>
    <change when="2010-02-19"><name>Laura Weakly</name> Initial Encoding</change>
    <change when="2010"><name>Sam Herley</name> OCR</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>

<text>


<body>

<head type="main">PRIVATE FISH PONDS</head>


<p>Kimball Graphic: As will be sen by an item in another column, State Game Warden Hedrick offers to furnish fish
for private ponds upon application to his department at Pierre. While the enterprise and proposition is 
laudable one, yet the Graphic questions and <choice><sic>pratical</sic><corr>practical</corr></choice> phases of it. Still more does it question the right
of the game commission to furnish fry for private ponds at the expense of the public game fund &#8212; if that is the 
intention. It is possible that the government furnishes the fry; we do not know as to that. If so, all very well 
and good. But even in such a case, if plenty of fish for stocking purposes are available it seems to us that there
are plenty of permanent lakes throughout the state that can take care of these fry more profitable to all 
concerned than by dumping them into private ponds of small areas that in the great majority of cases do not 
and cannot furnish a proper food supply for the growing <choice><sic>rry</sic></choice>. It is to be presumed that the game commission
makes a careful investigation before furnishing fish for stocking any body of water &#8212; it is hoped so at least.
Lake Andes was stocked with a tomato can full of little bullheads and an ordinary cream can full of black bass
fry originally, and in a few years the lake was so full of bullheads that you could actually shovel them out
at places where they sought the warm incoming water from the artesian wells. When the bass got big enough to
go foraging they feasted on the bullheads, and it is doubtful if any like lake or body of water anywhere in
the world ever saw as rapid increase of big mouthed black bass as happened at Lake Andes. But in teh last few years, 
both the bullheads and the bass have decreased rapidly, and so persistently and thoroughly is the lake fished
that now it is rare a bass is <choice><sic>whse</sic></choice> enough to remain in his native element past his second year. The large
bass are almost extinct.</p>
<p>Well, what we are getting at is this: With so perfect a body of water and food conditions as exist at Lake
Andes teh state game commission has a place to dump all hte fry they can spare &#8212; though it is such a perfect
black bass lake that it is to be hoped they will not stock it with anything else, lest it be bullheads to 
feed them with. There are a few pike in the lake, but they do not seem to thrive like the big mouths &#8212; at least
but few are caught. It is passing strange why there are not enough able-bodied sportsmen in Chas. Mix and
Douglas counties to see that the lake is stocked every year with bass. If you think that you can't exhaust
the supply already there you will find something different mighty soon.</p>

</body>
</text>
</TEI>