<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.2.0/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="cdn.water.lake.0001">
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title level="m" type="main">Not First Time Our Lake Was Waterless</title>
<title level="m" type="sub"></title>
<principal n="Nesheim, David A.">David Nesheim</principal>
</titleStmt>

<editionStmt>
<edition><date>2012</date></edition>
</editionStmt>
<publicationStmt>
<idno>cdn.water.lake.0001</idno>
 <authority>Casting Digital Nets: Fishery Modeling, Native Dispossession, and Dynamic History on the Great Plains</authority>
<distributor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln Libraries</distributor>
<address>
<addrLine>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</addrLine>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
<availability>
<p>Copyright &#169; 2012 by University of Nebraska, all rights reserved.
Items in the Archive may be shared in accordance with the Fair Use provisions
of U.S. copyright law.  Redistribution or republication on other terms, in
any medium, requires express written consent from the editor and advance
notification of the publisher, the Center for Digital Research in the Humanities.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>

<notesStmt>
<note type="summary">

</note>
</notesStmt>


<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="a" type="original">Not First Time Our Lake Was Waterless</title>
<title level="a"></title>
<title level="j">Lake Andes Wave</title>
<author></author>
<publisher></publisher>
<pubPlace></pubPlace>
<date when="1934-08-02"></date>
<biblScope type="page">1</biblScope>
</bibl>
</sourceDesc>

</fileDesc>

<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="water">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="sky">
<term></term>
</keywords>
 <keywords scheme="original" n="land">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="earth">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="keyword">
<term></term>
</keywords>
</textClass>
</profileDesc>

<revisionDesc>
    <change when="2012-11-13"><name>Laura Weakly </name> Fixed title</change>
    <change when="2010-06-01"><name>Erin Pedigo</name> Initial Encoding</change>
    <change when="2010"><name>Sam Herley</name> OCR</change>

</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>

<text>

<body>
<div1>

<head type="main">NOT FIRST TIME OUR LAKE WAS WATERLESS</head>

<p> Armour Herald: The water in Lake
Andes is now at its lowest ebb since
1894, at which time it was completely
dry. The earliest records available in
regard to the history of the lake come
to us from the soldiers of the Civil war,
who under General Sulley fought the Sioux
Indians in the Dakotas, following the outbreaks
in Minnesota and the New Ulm massacre.</p>

<p>These troops, the 6th Iowa cavalry, were
quartered at Fort Randall, during the winter
of '62 and '63. The soldiers of this command
say that during their campaigning in this
country the weather was very hot and dry, and
feed for their horses was very hard to get.
Although they traversed the country for miles
around the fort on both sides of the river,
they were unable to find water anywhere
except at the "Old Muddy". These boys left
many records in the form of diaries, reports,
etc., but no mention was ever made of a lake
where Andes now is. J.W. Hewitt, one of
Sully's troopers who passed away in 1917,
said that he had hunted buffalo for miles north
of the fort in 1863 and at that time our
lake contained no water.</p>

<p>Though we are unable to locate any records
in connection with the lake between 1863 and
1882, we find that in this last named year
the lake ran over. The water it is said by old
timers, ran north from Johnson's Bay into
Arcon lake, which is partly located on the
Gerald McGrath place south of Armour, thence
north, then east and southeast into Choteau
creek some distance south. It might be said
in passing that the original survey for the
spillway was from Johnson's Bay into Choteau
Creek through Artesian Creek, which empties
into Choteau.</p>

<p>From this time on the water receded, for in
1894, twelve years later the lake was dry again.
The years prior to this were dry and hot, those
who lived here at that time will verify this.</p>

<p>In "A History of South Dakota" by Frances
Holley copyrighted in 1890, the author says of
Andes lake: "It is situated in South Dakota,
fifteen miles from Fort Randall, twelve miles
from the Yankton Agency and seven miles from
the smart town of Armour, the present terminus
of the Chicago and Northwestern Railroad (Chicago,
Milwaukee St. Paul and Pacific). It was named for
Edward Andes, a surveyor for the American Fur
Company. This lake is fifteen miles long, one and
one-half miles wide, with an average depth of
fifteen feet, and is in the form of a
crescent. It has no visible outlet, but is fed by
two creeks that drain a large area of country west
and north; and there are no fish in the water,
but a reptile, from ten to fifteen inches long,
and termed the axolot. Around the lake there is a
great abundance of game . . .  Andes Lake
is very nearly in the center of the Yankton
Reserve; around its shady banks was the old
camping ground on the trail to the Pipestone
Quarry, from which the Indians for centuries have
made their pipes.</p>

<p>It was also a famous resort for buffalo and
important as a tanning place. Until within a
comparatively short time the adjacent country
was well timbered, where now there is only here
and there a scanty, low growth; but along its shores
plumed grasses nod and sway, as white winged gulls go
by."</p>

<p>At this time the lake was on the wane, due to dry
years which caused the hard times of 1894. 
After the period of drouth <sic>drought</sic> heavy snows filled the
lake again to reach its peak in 1920 it nearly ran
out a second time. Since then the water has steadily
receded until now it is nearly dry.</p>

<p>The artesian well at the north end known as the
Spot as well, is flowing as good as ever, but the
water only spreads out on the mud flat and
evaporates. The well across from Stony Point has
been inactive for some years as also the well
at the town of Lake Andes. There are two wells
at the state hatchery.</p>
</div1>

</body>
</text>
</TEI>
