<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.2.0/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="cdn.land.letter.0009">
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title level="m" type="main">rough fish life reports</title>
<title level="m" type="sub"></title>
<principal>David Nesheim</principal>
</titleStmt>

<editionStmt>
<edition><date>2010</date></edition>
</editionStmt>
<publicationStmt>
<idno>cdn.land.letter.0009</idno>
 <authority>Casting Digital Nets: Fishery Modeling, Native Dispossession, and Dynamic History on the Great Plains</authority>
<distributor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln Libraries</distributor>
<address>
<addrLine>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</addrLine>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>etcenter@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
<availability>
<p>Copyright &#169; 2010 by University of Nebraska, all rights reserved.
Items in the Archive may be shared in accordance with the Fair Use provisions
of U.S. copyright law.  Redistribution or republication on other terms, in
any medium, requires express written consent from the editor and advance
notification of the publisher, the Center for Digital Research in the Humanities.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>

<notesStmt>
<note type="summary">

</note>
</notesStmt>


<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="a">endangered fish life articles</title>
<title level="a"></title>
<title level="j">correspondence</title>
<author></author>
<publisher></publisher>
<pubPlace></pubPlace>
<date when="1930-11-28"></date>
<biblScope type="page">unknown</biblScope>
</bibl>
</sourceDesc>

</fileDesc>

<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="water">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="sky">
<term></term>
</keywords>
 <keywords scheme="original" n="land">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="earth">
<term></term>
</keywords>
</textClass>
</profileDesc>

<revisionDesc>
    <change when="2010-06-01"><name>Erin Pedigo</name> Initial Encoding</change>
    <change when="2010"><name>Sam Herley</name> OCR</change>

</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>

<text>

<body>
<div1>


			<p> 11/28, 1930.</p>

<p> Mr. Bob Ripple</p>
<p> Watertown S. Dak.</p>

	<p> Dear Bob.&#8212;</p> 

		<p> Just got home from Andes and wanted
to stop over and see you but it was to <sic>too</sic> late. pulled <sic>Pulled</sic>
several hauls but dident <sic>didn't</sic> get much. the <sic>The</sic> bigest <sic>biggest</sic> haul got 1400#, had twice as big a seine as last year too,
but couldn't find any carp. Caught lots of crappies
and believe me there <sic>they're</sic> nice this year they grew twice
the size they were last, the carp are pretty scarce
down there I think. I am going back there after
Christmas if its <sic>it's</sic> O. K. with you. I can get all the
fish around the wells at that time when they
come up for fresh water. Andes is a peculiar
lake to fish as you know.</p>

	<p> I am disgusted the way election went in our state
Bob, but dont <sic>don't</sic> forget when the opportunity comes I will
always remember you, every thing <sic>everything</sic> would of been O. K.
if things hadn't taken a flop here. but <sic>But</sic> we're 
setting pretty any way, altho <sic>although</sic> it perhaps will take
some time to get lined up.</p>

	<p> We were lucky enough to get Big Stone from north 
of the Islands to Browns Valley about 14 miles of the 
north end of the lake. Were just alowed <sic>allowed</sic> one big
seine in that portion of the lake.</p> 

	<p> Now Bob if its <sic>it's</sic> in your power to give Jerry
the S. Dak. side wish you would.</p> 

	<p> The people here are all satisfied to have
one big crew on each side of the lake as
it would furnish work for so many people here,
I surely would like to see you here on this job
this winter. dont <sic>Don't</sic> mention this to any fisherman.
if <sic>If</sic> you happen this way call me up.</p> 

				<p> Yours Truly</p>
				    <p> Moose</p>
</div1>

<div1>

		<p> Brookings, Dec. 7, 1930.</p>

<p> Mr. Everett Randall,</p>
<p> Browns Valley, Minnesota.</p>

<p> Dear Mr. Randall:</p>

	<p> Have not been at Watertown until the other
day since my headquarters are at Dudley Hotel, Brookings
for the time being so am tardy in answering yours of Nov.
28th.</p> 

	<p> The Lake Andes work turned out about as I
had expected during open water fishing and I agree with
you in that when the ice forms of about a certain thickness
the remaining carp will be found bunched up around the wells,
especially the north well.         Hope you do go back down
there and that you get enough fish to warrant the expense.
Dont <sic>Don't</sic> think but what you will encounter a fine bunch of stuff
at this north well and no one in South Dakota wants to see
that lake cleaned of carp more than I do.</p>

	<p> Nothing much was done at our last commission
meeting relative to either Big Stone or Traverse and so far
as I can see our commission had no idea of going into Big
Stone at least.     Traverse will have to be watched during
this low water etc.      If Minnesota is really going into
Big Stone it is a surprise to me and I do not know just what
our commission will do in this latter event.</p>

	<p> Was glad to learn from a late copy of the 
People's Press of Sisseton that they had corrected an article
they ran in a former issue in reference to myself and seining
operations.   I dont <sic>don't</sic> like to be misquoted and have nothing to
take back that I have ever said relative to seining or rough
fish work while in South Dakota.</p>

	<p> Notice your comment Everett and thank you for
same, Minnesota is a wonderful state of waters and fish and 
I sure would relish the opportunity to be in that work at Big
Stone or any where else that the damnable carp are coming out
to make way for better fishing.    Expect to be over in that
locality soon looking up shallow waters etc. at a number of
our lakes and sloughs.</p> 
			
				<p> Very truly yours,</p>
				         <p> R. L. Ripple. </p>
</div1>


<div1>

								<p> Jan. 7, 1931.</p>

<p> Mr. R. L. Ripple,</p>
<p> C/o Dudly Hotel,</p>
<p> Brookings, S. D.</p>

<p> Dear Bob:</p>

	<p> I have yours with remittance of $507.09, which same has
been credited to Madison operation.</p>

	<p> Just received a telephone communication from McBride at
Lake Andes this morning and he states that arrangements have been made,
through Hank Schemmer, with the owners of a shallow lake in Bennett
County, for large quantity of bullheads.   This lake is reported to
be teeming with under-size bullheads and Mac would like to have several
truck loads of them transferred to Lake Andes. He states that arrange-
ments will be made to have "Moose" Randall do the seining for them
when he returns to Lake Andes for the purpose of completing his opera-
tions on that lake.</p>

	<p> In this bullhead work, they would like to have our 500'
bullhead net which was sent into Huron during the Fair. Do not know
just where this net is but if you will kindly advise me where it can be 
picked up, I will arrange to have it taken to Lake Andes at an early
date. They have gotten in touch with Randall and he advises them that
he has a bag which he can attach to this net, which equipment would
make it possible for them to take out great quantities of bullheads
which infest the lake in Bennett County.</p>

	<p> Kindly advise me at once where this net can be secured, so
that I may arrange to have it sent to Andes.</p>

				<p> Very truly yours,</p>

				<p> O. H. Johnson, Director</p>
				<p> Department of Game and Fish.</p>

<p> OHJ: AW</p>
</div1>

<div1>

			<p> Brookings, January 16, 1931.</p>

<p> Mr. O. H. Johnson, Director,</p>
<p> Department of Game &amp; Fish,</p>
<p> Pierre, South Dakota.</p>

<p> Dear Mr. Johnson:</p>

	<p> So that you may know what move I have made
toward the bullhead work contemplated for Lake Andes through
the getting of these fish from Scotchmans lake down in Bennet
County, will say as follows.     I would greatly prefer doing this
work with me own me <sic>men</sic> so far as possible and our own equipment, like
nets, trucks, etc.</p>

	<p>Had Lester meet me here at Brookings last night
also got Schemmer on the phone to settle some things regarding lake,
depth of lake, how far from habitation, etc.    Telephone call was
$1.25 and worth it before going down there as I intend sending
a full line of equiptment <sic>equipment</sic>, tanks, seines, hoopnets, air compressor,
ropes, chisels, running boards etc.    This will all go on our big
new body Ford truck and I will await word from Lester about conditions
for getting the bullheads etc.</p>

	<p> With your permission I have gotten hold of Fred Curtis
our warden at Huron, he will go through with Lester and if things
pan out after a severe trial, Lester may have Dutch shoot across
with another man from Rapid City hatchery for man power.
Understand the nearest farm house is about two miles distant from
the lake they will work.    Depth of lake is about six feet in the
deeper parts so I am not sending our big twelve foot seine, but am
sending about 600 ft. of eight ft. leaders that will serve better.
There is little about nets and netting that Lester does not know
and if a center bag is necessary, Lester will make one up from one 
of the leaders.</p>

	<p> If we can make use of our new one inch mesh hoopnets,
that will be fine and I think we can.    Bullheads supposed to run in
size from 6 inches to 14 inches, Schemmer says.    Will keep you
posted in this work.    Lester and equiptment <sic>equipment</sic> etc. will no doubt be
at Winner on Sunday night to connect with Schemmer if he wants to go
out to lake with them.</p>

					<p>Very truly yours,</p>
						<p>R. L. Ripple</p>

<p> Mr. Johnson:</p>

	<p> If the Bullhead work at Scotchmans lake pans
out as we hope it will, I will arrange to have Dutch bring
our International truck accross <sic>across</sic> from Rapid City to this lake
so we can keep two trucks running while the work is on.</p>

	<p> I am keeping our SECOND POND TRUCK with Lawrence
Sorenson in case I have to have that truck for work in these
parts for lake areation etc.</p>

					<p> R. L. Ripple</p>
</div1>

<div1>

				<p> Brookings, January 19, 1931.</p>

<p> Mr. O. H. Johnson, Director,</p>
<p> Department of Game &amp; Fish,</p>
<p> Pierre, South Dakota.</p>

<p> Dear Mr. Johnson:</p>                                 <p> Carp Seining At Lake Mitchell</p>

	<p> Last fall during open water it was the desire
of some people at Mitchell to have the Russian Colonists
seine their lake to remove the carp and I told Mr. Peterson
also Mr. Noble that I would endeavor to let them know when
I could get away from from other work in order to make an
experimental seine haul.    Although admitting that I have
failed to connect with the Russians to make such haul owing
to stress of other work, I admit that I had little faith in
anything worth while <sic>worthwhile</sic>, the Russians would be able to accomplish
with such small equiptment <sic>equipment</sic> as they have.</p>

	<p> It seems to me, knowing the depths etc. of Lake
Mitchell, that any seining operations attempted there other
than to attempt to shut off the carp in the bays during spawning
season of such fish, would meet with failure by any crew unless
equipped with very deep seines for the purpose or as we used 
out at Orman Dam.          In other words special equiptment <sic>equipment</sic> would
have to made use of to accomplish much.        Then to, there
is the matter of green stumps and other matter at the bottom 
of that artificial lake, the old creek bed at the upper end
where it could be expected carp would hold out.</p>

	<p> Further, it is my opinion that the carp in a general
way, speaking of numbers, consist of small stuff that has naturally
propagated during the couple years the lake has been raised.
It appears to me that here is one lake where if anything worth
while <sic>worthwhile</sic> is attempted in removing carp, the work should be started
among the bays and upper end of lake during the carp spawning
time and even then it is a guess of any man what could be done.</p>

	<p> Any netting operation down there would please
those people in showing up how numerous the game fishes may
be and this information is desired by them as much as to get
out the carp. I for one am not anxious to get into any additional
rough fishing operations the balance of this winter since we
have enough grief along the line on the hand at present time.</p> 
</div1>

<div1>

<p> Mr. O. H. Johnson, . . 2.</p>

	<p> If, as you say, Mr. Jerry Wilson of the Lake
Andes seining operations wishes to make an experimental
seine haul at Lake Mitchell just after finishing at Andes
for the purpose of determining what is there and what can
be expected in being able to seine the lake at all, then that
will be fine with me.    Will be more than glad to be on
hand to supervise such haul and will hope for its success.
No one can be more interested in getting carp out of Lake 
Mitchell than myself but I know its a hard nut to crack in
such work.</p>

	<p> I am convinced that game fishes are in Lake Mitchell
in great numbers, however, this should be determined previous
to any hook and line fishing there to the public.
I am not making any guess when I say that the Black Bass, Bullheads,
and Wall Eyed Pikes we have stocked the lake with, have all done
fine.    Also there have been some fine natural hatches of game
fishes there.    An experimental seine haul during this winter
and if they can come in clean, might determine something about
the numbers of game fishes.</p>

	<p> If I can spare Lester and if you think it advisable,
I might send him to Lake Mitchell with a few of our big hoop-nets
in the near future and if he could find the proper depth of water
to keep the nets from freezing to the ice, he might catch game
fish in numbers enough to determine some thing <sic>something</sic>.
Open water would be far better for this, after our Pike work
would be out of the way.</p>

			       <p> Very truly yours,</p>
					<p> R. L. Ripple</p>
</div1>


<div1>

						<p> January 27, 1931.</p>

<p> Mr. R. L. Ripple,</p>
<p> Brookings, S. D.</p>

<p>Dear Bob:</p>

	<p> Have yours of the 25th, also remittance covering rough
fish work at Oakwood. Glad to learn that operations are about com-
pleted on Fish Lake and that Smith will get started on Hendricks.
Getting some work down on <unclear reason="illegible" /> will also help matters consider-
able <sic>considerably</sic>.</p>

	<p> Just had a telephone call from Duffy and he states that 
Randall is back at Lake Andes. Am afraid if this weather continues
the operations of Andes are not going to be very extensive.</p>
		
						<p> Very truly yours,</p>
							<p> O. H. Johnson, Director,</p>
<p> OHJ:AW</p> 						<p> Department of Game and Fish.</p>
</div1>


<div1>

				  <p> Watertown, Nov. 9, 1930. </p>

<p>Mr. O. H. Johnson, Director,</p>
<p> Department of Game &amp; Fish,</p>
<p> Pierre, South Dakota.</p>

<p> Dear Mr. Johnson:</p>

	<p> Enclosed please find report of
the rough fishing operations at the various lakes
covering everything of interest to this date
Sunday, Nov. 9th.</p>

	<p> Might say here that I made that trip
to Cottonwood lake out of Redfield and the reason I
did not get over there earlier was because I hated
to take that big jump knowing that they would not be
ready to go ahead as they should and because I have
been so busy with the bigger work at other lakes.
Well I notified Mr. Klebsch through our Game Farm
what day I would be there and to get ready to make
a seine haul upon that date,        Found the day a fine
one upon arrival and finally located Mr. Klebsch in
Redfield.     Said he had been beside him-self <sic>himself</sic> in
trying to get together an equiptment <sic> equipment</sic> and thought he
would now be able to do so and would let me know through
our Mr. Hodginsa few days ahead of when he would start.
I gave him to understand that nothing short of proper
equiptment <sic>equipment</sic> would fill the bill Cottonwood because we
did not wish to go in there and make any fizzle of the work.</p>

	<p> Mr. Klebsch is going to work out O. K.
with a little coaching and I am confident that our work
at Cottonwood will turn out O. K.    Told Klebsch it was
his own and work out the thing himself alone it would be
better and that the people over there would feel better.</p> 
				
				<p> Very truly yours,</p>
					<p> R. L. Ripple</p>
</div1>


<div1>
			
					<p> Watertown, Nov. 9, 1930.</p>

<p> Mr. O. H. Johnson, Director,</p>
<p> Department of Game &amp; Fish,</p>
<p> Pierre, South Dakota.</p>

<p>Dear Mr. Johnson:</p>				 <p> POINSETT LAKE</p>

	<p> The big haul of carp and buffalo brought in
on Saturday, Nov. 1st, will run to possibly about 50 tons of
one half each, carp and buffalo, it may turn out more.
Several hauls had been made previous to this date at Poinsett
of a number of tons each so they have had plenty of rough fish
on hand in the face of what is generally known as a poor market
during this warm weather and all the rough fish going to the
big eastern cities from Virginia etc.</p>

	<p> The two rough fish crews have had enough to do
during this past week in shipping what fish they could, making
additional holding crates etc. without further seining and I have
this day told them not toget any more LARGE hauls in until this
mess of stuff on hand is seen to be cleaned up.       We cannot just
for the sake of seining, bring in great amounts of rough fish to
be sold for a song when such fish can be had later when conditions
all around will be different.      Some loss will have to be
taken in prices on this stuff and on some that died from heavy
seas in cribs etc.    However I am on top of this work and will
determine conditions as they arrive, in the best manner possible.</p>

	<p> One carload has been shipped east, price uncertain
as yet, 57 boxes iced to Chicago, price uncertain, 140 boxes iced 
to New York, price 4 cents on no. 2, 7 cents on no. 1. About 150 boxes
to the east, price uncertain at present.       Thousands of pounds
sold on the ground, locally.       Carp brining some better price
than buffalo at present time, mostly buffalo being shipped from
Virginia.     My information from CARP BUYERS on the ground,
and from $35.00 worth of messages sent out by Carl Kelsen is
that the market is really poor at present.    Also gain this
information from Mr. Joe Kiner who shipped a carload from Madison
yesterday.     The whole thing is rather a stall to govern prices
perhaps but you know Mr. Johnson, that prices will be normal
when cold weather sets in.    Walter Bushaver whom you I presume
know about as an agent for large eastern concern, was on the ground
at Lake Poinsett last Wednesday.    His information is the same
as from others but during last winter I came to have a lot of 
respect for this man's say-so and his seeming honesty.
He purchased all fish from the Hendricks work.       He is confident
that prices will be up soon and got to Carl Kelsen about some
contract on prices for Poinsett.    Carl took it all in and came
to me and my advise <sic>advice</sic> to Kelsen was that it would be time to talk
about contract prices after our contracts were out to the different 
fishermen in the field at that the matter would have to be taken
up with our office at any rate.</p>
</div1>


<div1>

<p> Mr. Johnson . . 2.</p>          <p> POINSETT LAKE CONTINUED</p> 

	<p> It is my opinion that we cannot make contracts with
the two crews at Lake Poinsett and set a price per pound to our
department to govern during this coming winter, until we know
more about the prices that will govern later when market is right.
However I wish we had some dicker for the stuff at this time but
since Lake Poinsett is a living mass of rough fish, we should not
cry over a little spilt milk so speaking.   I will see that we
take no loss over and above what is necessary to properly govern
Poinsett work to the time things will be on the feet.
Checking up all shipping bills and local sales very closely.
Our work at Lake Poinsett this winter will be a lesson to everyone
concerned in the well-fare <sic>welfare</sic> of game fish, what the dirty water hogs
are capable of doing when left alone.     It will prove such a 
lesson as I have wished to prove for the good of game fishes in the 
years to come.    Lamentable beyond all description are the
conditions at Lake Poinsett, but it is well that in the face of all
the damnable carp etc. there are a remnant of the old folks left
of the game fish ranks.    Our stockings of Wall-Eyed-Pike fry
are showing up in the seine hauls by the hundreds and that fact
is very pleasing to the public interested in Poinsett.</p> 

				<p> OAKWOOD LAKES</p> 

	<p> At this date Sunday, Nov. 9th, they must have on
hand at Oakwood lakes about 45 tons of rough fish, moslt <sic>most</sic> all
carp of large size, just about like the Hendricks stuff last winter,
fat and fit as a fiddle.    This stuff is good for sore eyes to
CARP BUYERS and so Oakwood lakes have been good producers of carp.
A single haul at Oakwood lakes the other day, brought in about 
25 tons of these carp and somebody at Brookings said, Ripple you
are going to <sic>too</sic> far, there arent <sic>aren't</sic> many carp in Oakwood lakes.
Well history will be made for game fish in these wonderful lakes
this winter, I figure it will take quite a long train all told,
to haul the carp from there.    Please remember this is wonderul
stuff.    Have made arrangements with this crew to seine the game
fish from Turtle lake and Round lake that conncet <sic>connect</sic> with Oakwood lakes
during high water, they are now dis-connected and must be rescued.
A count will be made of all game fish we take from those two lakes,
over into Oakwood lakes proper.    If this market dont <sic>don't</sic> change, we
may fool the wise acres for a time by placing a heap of carp in
this Turtle lake to get out later when market is right.
Would like to sound out rough fish market for some time yet previous
to making our price to the state, what wonderful stuff this is.</p> 
</div1>


<div1>

<p> Mr. Johnson . . 4.</p>                             <p> RESCUE OPERATIONS </p>

	<p> I have not had the help of any of my crew except a day
or two at Lake Alice in rescue work or anything else, being content
to confine Lester, Dutch, Atchison, Kiner, and Sorenson to the 
very necessary work of putting in the new well, pipe-line and
other work at our Kampeska hatchery.    They will finish there
in a couple days and most of them with trucks will shoot west to
get those trout out of our Rapid hatchery.     Might possibly
have done something about rescue work with these men in a small way
but I cannot leave anything un-done <sic>undone</sic> at the Kampeksa hatchery that
would spell bad luck for our Pike hatching next spring.
Next spring's hatching must be bigger and better than ever to
stock these carp wallows when the carp are removed and they will
get plenty of Pike next season.    Will look into that matter of
Black Bass stranded down at Flandreau etc.    With all this work
at hand the carp lakes and my crews going west soon, I feel that
after I make a check-up of places like Lake John etc. I can send
report to the department for their next meeting when a program can
be mapped out.</p> 

	<p> I would like to call your attention Mr. Johnson, to what
is getting to be common talk by people around these lakes being
seined, I have heard so much of it lately.    They want to know
if the state is getting what is coming to it in the matter of
money derived from the rough fish.   It just seems that people
want to see our department get all they can from this work.
I can see among those crowds of people, so many hundreds of friends
of the Department of Game &amp; Fish and darn few people hollering
about getting out the rough fish.   It is true that Poinsett is 
going to rough up rough fish this winter, it is true to <sic>too</sic> that there
will be many grades and small stuff as well as no. 1 ones by the 
hundreds of thousands of lbs.    Oakwood lakes will turn out
wonderful market stuff with small percentage of small stuff and 
presume thinking will have to be done when contracts are let along
the line of prices, it will be no fun to do it.</p>

	<p>When my crew and trucks go west, I will keep one man
and truck with me for possible use transferring game fish.</p>

					<p> Very truly yours,</p>
						<p> R. L. Ripple</p>
</div1>

</body>
</text>
</TEI>

