<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.2.0/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="cdn.land.letter.0006">
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title level="m" type="main">Johnson, Ripple, and Dutch correspondence</title>
<title level="m" type="sub"></title>
<principal>David Nesheim</principal>
</titleStmt>

<editionStmt>
<edition><date>2010</date></edition>
</editionStmt>
<publicationStmt>
<idno>cdn.land.letter.0006</idno>
 <authority>Casting Digital Nets: Fishery Modeling, Native Dispossession, and Dynamic History on the Great Plains</authority>
<distributor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln Libraries</distributor>
<address>
<addrLine>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</addrLine>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>etcenter@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
<availability>
<p>Copyright &#169; 2010 by University of Nebraska, all rights reserved.
Items in the Archive may be shared in accordance with the Fair Use provisions
of U.S. copyright law.  Redistribution or republication on other terms, in
any medium, requires express written consent from the editor and advance
notification of the publisher, the Center for Digital Research in the Humanities.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>

<notesStmt>
<note type="summary">

</note>
</notesStmt>


<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="a">Johnson-pickups correspondence</title>
<title level="a"></title>
<title level="j">correspondence</title>
<author></author>
<publisher></publisher>
<pubPlace></pubPlace>
<date when="1935-05-09"></date>
<biblScope type="page">unknown</biblScope>
</bibl>
</sourceDesc>

</fileDesc>

<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="water">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="sky">
<term></term>
</keywords>
 <keywords scheme="original" n="land">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="earth">
<term></term>
</keywords>
</textClass>
</profileDesc>

<revisionDesc>
<change when="2010-08-05"><name> Rhiannon Root</name> Proofread</change>
    <change when="2010-06-01"><name>Erin Pedigo</name> Initial Encoding</change>
    <change when="2010"><name>Sam Herley</name> OCR</change>

</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>

<text>

<body>
<div1>

<p> May 9, 1935</p> 

<p> Mr. R. L. Ripple,
Watertown, S. D.</p>

<p> Dear Bob:

	We have an authorization from the State Purchas-
ing Department covering the 125" wheelbase International
pickup, complete with enclosed cab, steel pickup box, oil
bath, air cleaner and 5 heavy-duty 6-ply casings and tubes.</p> 

	<p> The low bidder on this outfit was M. F. Heintz
of Florence, South Dakota, but would suggest that you call
at the International Harvester Company's office in Water-
town and find out whether delivery will be made at Water-
town or Florence.</p> 

	<p> The Ford pickup at Lake Andes is being turned
in on this job and I am writing Al Van Leur at Woonsocket,
who is now using it, asking him to drive it to Watertown
within the next few days. Be sure to remove the state plates
from the trade-in and send them to us here at Pierre, also
send us a description of the new International so that we
may secure State plates for it.</p> 

		       <p> Very truly yours,</p>
			
		
				<p> O. H. Johnson, Director
                        Department of Game and Fish</p> 
<p> OHJ:AW</p>
</div1>

<div1>

<p> Watertown, May 28, 1935.</p> 

<p> Mr. O. H. Johnson, Director,
Department of Game and Fish,
Pierre, South Dakota.</p> 

<p> Dear Mr. Johnson:</p> 

	<p> In order to avoid any mistake in reference
to what kind of fish carrying tanks are to be used on the
three new Pickups, I would like to suggest that the men
who are to use the other two outfits may not have the same
opinion that I have in the makeup of a tank.</p>
 
	<p> We have given much thought to a proper tank
for our use on the International Pickup and this enclosed
plan suits us to a nicety however we realize it may cost more
than we can afford to invest in such equiptment <sic>equipment</sic>.</p> 

	<p> Talking with Chairman, Dr. Fankhauser at
Pickerel lake hatchery recently I learned that he has some
definite views relative to size, shape and other features
of a proper fish carrying tank for their Pickup and it may
be that the boys at Rapid City have like wise <sic>likewise</sic> and so it would
be well to let them go over our plan before hand <sic>beforehand</sic>.</p> 

	<p> Dr. Fankhauser's idea in one respect was that
the tank should fill in the total inside of the rear Pickup
box or body and not have the tank to <sic>too</sic> high.   If this is the
plan they want, this plan of ours can be made to fit the need
if they find the balance of the plan suitable.   After explainging <sic>explaining</sic>
to the Dr. why we would elect to use a tank and Pickup body box
he may have changed his mind however I don't know.
We know from experience that the smaller tank with deeper water
will work out much better on the road in reference to water
splash and sway and thats <sic>that's</sic> the main reason for a higher tank.
The body-box measurements of the other two Pickups may differ
from ours so that would have to be taken into consideration
since this plan is drawn to fit what we want on the International.</p> 

	<p> The tank cover we would select would be the
two piece affair, hinged at both sides and hasps in the middle.
This type of cover would be far superior to the one piece cover.
	Please note on plan, the weight of laod <sic>load</sic>, 26"
of water, 1976 pounds.     Thats <sic>that's</sic> a great plenty to carry on single
tires.</p> 

					<p> Very truly yours,</p> 
				    <p>  R. L. Ripple</p>
</div1>

<div1>

<opener>
<dateline>Mr. Ripple                              Omaha, Nebraska 
Kampeska Hotel                         26, 1935
Watertown
   S. Dak.</dateline>

<salute> Dear Sir:</salute>
</opener>
	<p> I received a letter from Mr. Johnson
who says that you are fishing Swan 
Lake.</p>

	<p> Please let me know what you are
getting now.</p> 

			<p> Yours Truly
			Sam Flax</p> 
</div1>

<div1>

<p> Watertown, October 30, 1935.</p>

<p> Mr. Sam Flax
1402 North 24th, Street,
Omaha, Nebraska.</p> 

<p> Dear Mr. Flax:</p>

	<p> Replying to your letter October 26th, in
reference to our rough fish removal work to be done down
at Swan Lake near Viborg, South Dakota will say that we
are at this time moving our equiptment <sic>equipment</sic> to said lake so
that very soon we will be under way.</p> 

	<p> Just as soon as we have the opportunity to
make a few seine hauls I will acquaint you with what the
catch consists of however I am informed that buffalo are
more numerous than the carp in that lake.</p>

			<p> Very truly yours,
			Department of Game and Fish,
			R. L. Ripple
			Supt. of Fisheries,
			R. L. Ripple, General Delivery,
			Viborg, South Dakota.</p>
</div1>

<div1>

<p> Watertown, September 27, 1935.</p>

<p> Mr. W. W. Aitken,
State Biologist,
Iowa Conservation Commission,
State Capitol,
Des Moines, Iowa.</p> 

<p> Dear Sir:</p>
	
	<p> I have just received a copy of your letter under
date September 5th, together with a letter from our Director,
Mr. O. H. Johnson with the request that I make reply to your
inquiry in reference to areation of low water lakes.
During the past several years of severe drought we have had
a considerable number of lakes to contend with that either went
dry entirely or so low that all fish-life had to be removed to
deeper lakes.</p>

	<p> May it be understood that the air compressors we made
use of were not a cure-all, however we consider the results
attained from their use payed us a hundred fold for the expense
we went to in the matter of proper equiptment <sic>equipment</sic>. </p>

	<p> Although we had a number of fish rescue crews in the
field seining the fish-life from many of the low water lakes we could
not keep pace with the situation and that was when the air compressor
work came in and through their use we were able to tide many lakes
over the winter months.    The average depth of our lakes from which
we either removed all fish or used the compressors to tide through
the winters was about 5ft so that when ice came to the depth of
28 to 34 inches we had a real problem to contend with.</p>

	<p> In some of our lakes the water depth under the ice was 
only about 2ft. still we brought through the fish and such lakes
were well stocked with native fish such as northern pike, black bass,
perch, crappies, etc.   In a few instances where we could not get
to certain lakes but was making use of the compressors in lakes
nearby we had a loss of fish in the waters not worked with the 
compressors while no loss was had where we worked same.
Such lakes were in the same condition as to being heavily minerali-
zed, depth, size etc.    We have plenty of proof in reference to
the value of areating low lakes through winters of heavy ice etc.</p>

	<p> Our lakes are of course prairie lakes for the greater
part with a gumbo bottom and heavy vegetation.    We found of 
course that where wall-eyed-pike and crappies were the principal
varieties of fish in a lake and since they make use of the deeper
portion during the winter months, our efforts with the compressors
were more confined to the central portion of the lake.</p> 
</div1>

<div1>

<p> Mr. W. W. Aitken, 2,</p> 

	<p> Lakes containing black bass of the large mouth variety,
bluegills and some other varieties that take more to the bays and
more shallow water areas were worked accordingly.</p>

	<p> I recall the winter several years  back when we were
seining carloads of buffalo and carp from one of our largest lakes
some 7,500 acres in extent at a time when the fish were coming in
at each seine haul in bad condition from the very shallow water
under the ice and we had some 6 carloads in our carp cribs that 
were so weak one would not think anything could bring them around
so I hustled our large compressor over from a neighbor lake and after
a couple hours among the cribs areating the fish they came through
and buyers eagerly grabbed them off.    During the balance of that
winter there were many times when our compressors saved many carloads
of rough fish in our cribs at different lakes.</p>

	<p> There were some instances among lakes where the water
under the ice got so low we could not hope to save the fish through
any means except to open same to public fishing with a netting progra <sic>program</sic>
allowing so many feet of seine or gillnets to the person, either
previous to the freeze-up or after ice came.</p> 

	<p> The average size of the lakes we used the air compre-
ssors on run from several miles long and mile wide down to those
much smaller say a mile long and quarter to half mile wide. Only
one large compressor was used at each lake and this outfit
was moved from lake to lake as needed.    We used several smaller
outfits however we found the larger unit more adapted to the work.</p>

	 <p> The following is a line-up of our equiptment <sic>equipment</sic>.
	Pump-Lehmann Bros. Newark, N. Jersey, Size F. (2)
Rated at 78 Cu. ft. air per minute at 200 revolutions.
Power-8. h. p. 2 cylinder Le Roi gas engine, radiator cooled- working
through a 3:57 to 1 reduction gear and belted to pump.
The whole apparatus enclosed in a Trailer House.
Because of the enormous lubrication drag in the air pump when
freezing cold, belt drive is used to avoid possible breakage of
working parts.    It is advisable to warm pump with blow torch
before starting and as soon as it is running direct blow torch flame
into pump air inlet umtil <sic>until</sic> pump operates normally.   The heat of
the engine keeps the 7x10 house very confortable <sic>comfortable</sic> and the pump uses
the warmed air for areation.   The method then is to have wooden
pipes made of 1x6 or 1x8 boards frozen into the ice well in advance
of the time areation is to be done.    These pipes are long enough
to extend at least 3 or 4 inches below the ice when it is thickest
and 6 or 10 inches above to make them easy to locate under the snow.
Their location is of course marked by a tree limb or something on
the ice. The idea then is to put the hose from the air pump (a
length of 2 inch suction is the hose used)down through this wooden pipe
after the ice has been chisled from inside to the water
and in under the ice far enough that the air does not escape back
out through the pipe.</p>

<p>No method of air diffusion is used on the end of the hose as it
is believed that the air in contact with the water under the ice
is all that is needed, the water being deficient in oxygen will
absorb oxygen as well as if the air was finally diffused. 
Another point is the large air bubbles will go way off under the
ice and in that way take air a considerable distance from the
point of pumping.   Air pockets from pumping have been located
nearly a half mile from the pump.   We endeavor to check on the 
oxygen along about 3 to 4 weeks after the freeze-up in the
questionable lakes and then a week or tow <sic>two</sic> later make a second
check. From the two figures we project at that rate of oxygen loss
the approximate time the oxygen content will lower to about 2 parts 
per million.   It is then planned to start areation some in 
advance of this time with the air pump.    As to merits-for the
cost it is beleived <sic>believed</sic> most practical and successful.</p>

	<p> One cubic ft. of air at sea level contains enough oxygen to
saturate about 37 ft. cu. ft. of water.   At winter temperature and
under this condition saturation is about 7 times more oxygen
than lake fish require. So we assume that 7 times our 37 is
sufficient air or to compensate for differences of air pressure
and pump inefficiency we use a ratio of one cu. ft. of air to 200
cu. ft. of water.    This has been shown to all indications very
satisfactory results.       With our 75 cu. ft. pump it is possible
to treat about 15000 cu. ft. of water per minute or 20 acre ft.
per hour.      By estimating the acre ft. of water under the ice
and dividing by the 20 it is possible to reach a satisfactory
estimate of the pumping hours required and then an oxygen analysis
about a week or less after the pumping will show the
accomplishments.  This method will give spots in the lake
well areated and of course places not so well areated but this
occurs in the lakes even when they are not artificially areated.</p> 

<p> Pump cost about $168.00
Gas engine "     200.00
Assembly &amp; Trailer 125.00</p> 

<p> Will use about 10 gallons of gasoline per 24 hours.</p> 

<p> If there should be any further data desired relative to this matter
kindly address to R. L. Ripple, Kampeska Hotel, Watertown, S. D.</p> 

						<p> Very truly yours,</p>
						<p> R. L. Ripple</p> 
</div1>

<div1>

<p> Viborg, November 2, 1935.</p>

<p> Mr. O. H. Johnson, Director,
Department of Game and Fish,
Pierre, South Dakota.</p> 

<p> Dear Mr. Johnson: </p>                                         <p> Swan Lake, Viborg.</p> 

	<p> Sorry to say things dont <sic>don't</sic> look very
good to us down here today with Swan lake <sic>Lake</sic> partly covered
with ice and freezing more every minute.    Not enough
open water to attempt any seine haul with weather conditions
looking more like mid-winter than usually at this time of
the season.</p>

	<p> Coming south from Watertown yesterday
morning to find Poinsett and Campell lakes all frozen over
we had hoped this far south to find things at least so we
could make a few hauls but there is nothing to be done about
it.</p>

	<p> If we only knew what to expect of the
weather because the average fall does not find this lake
freezing up until at least the middle of November.
If this freeze-up dont <sic>don't</sic> let up, there wont <sic>won't</sic> be any use of
the crew staying around here waiting for heavy enough ice
for ice fishing so all I can do is wait a reasonable length of 
time for the lake to open up or forget this job for the time being.</p>

	<p> If the freeze-up continues it will be just
to <sic>too</sic> bad to have this job on our hands to the detriment of
the big job at Kampeska lake for ice fishing.</p>

	<p> Talking with Pete Hansen whom we are staying
with here at the lake and who has had considerable experience
with the rough fish situation here, we dont <sic>don't</sic> learn much about
what can be expected with our big seine more than the stuff is
not so numerous as many people think.</p>

	<p> Looks as though a fine local market could be
expected combined with the Sioux City guys however there is
quite a flurry from some Farmers' Union outfit that say we cannot
remove and sell Swan lake rough fish legally etc.
This latter flurry will wear itself out with proper handling
so I have no fear of the future, its something alike to our
little trouble at Lake Poinsett and is not at all serious.</p> 

					<p> Very truly yours,</p>
					<p> R. L. Ripple</p>
</div1>

<div1>

			<p> Viborg, South Dakota.</p>
			<p>November 2, 1935.</p>

<p> Mr. A. N. Herrboldt,
County Auditor,
Ipswich, South Dakota.</p>

<p> Dear Mr. Herrboldt:</p> 

	<p> I am very pleased to have your letter 
under date of October 30th, in reference to the well-fare <sic>welfare</sic>
of the fish-life contained in the Mina dam during the
coming winter months because it shows the correct interest
you have for the future of hook and line fishing in that
territory which is bound to come.</p> 

	<p> We have been so terribly busy during the
past summer stocking hundreds of dams and other new waters
combined with the remaining natural lakes that I just havent <sic>haven't</sic>
personally gotten to Mina dam however my impression is from
an early visit there previous to the dam going in is that
water holes along the creek run containing creek <unclear reason="typo" /> and
shiner minnows along with other fish food would find their
way into the dam proper when water came which did come.
It is my opinion that there is more fish food in Mina dam
than one would suppose other than someone who understands
the workings of nature etc.     This is a thing I would liked <sic>like</sic>
to have checked on had the opportunity been my good fortune
however I am not worrying very much about fish-life not going
through the winter at Mina dam with a twenty foot depth and
several hundred acres in extent.    It is surprising what
nature accomplishes in the way of fish food as water bugs
and other animal-life in one season in an area of water the
size of Mina dam or any part of its size.</p>

	<p> Fish must have food of course and it is as 
proper to introduce fish food minnows as shiners and chubs
of the minnow family of fishes as it is to introduce stock
fish themselves especially in dams or artificial lakes where
there is no creek bed or opportunity for minnows to gain
entrance into the dam proper.    Food minnows should no doubt
be introduced into Mina dam if available and I would advise
this at any time, however, the old CARP question of rough fish
getting into new dams bobs up and no transfer of minnows should
be undertaken unless some warden or other qualified person that 
knows fish can be on hand to sort out the best of waters the
carp and other rough fish minnows that may be found in the 
source of supply.</p>
</div1>

<div1>

<p> Mr. A. E. Herrboldt 2,</p>

	<p> Having been in the propagation of fish
or more properly the farming of fish for some 40 years I
have stumbled onto some things that I wish I had another
hundred years to devote to and one is the fight against
that wolf of waters the CARP.    This because I know him
to be the smartest fish in fresh water and one that had no
business along side <sic>alongside</sic> our native fishes to wreck and ruin
and represent the greatest mistake every <sic>ever</sic> made in this country
in the introduction of wild-life.   That is why I am down here
at Swan lake, Viborg at this time to remove the wolves and
place them in wooden boxes packed away where the only good carp
are to be found, they are no good alive in waters.</p>

	<p> I have mentioned this carp strongly to you
because I wish to show how very much pains should be taken
not to get them introduced into your dam or any other where
from the nature of the bottoms of such dams they possibly
could never be eradicated.</p> 

	<p> A great portion of the stock fish placed
in Mina dam were young in age and small insize <sic> in size</sic> so that their
main food supply the first season would consist of animal life
in the way of water-bug-life that nature seldom fails to bring
with its vegetation etc.    In the matter of food, fish are
some what <sic>somewhat</sic> dormant during the winter months.</p>

	<p> My advice is not to worry about the fish
and food supply in Mina dam this winter and if at any time
there is found some place where creek minnows as chubs and
shiners can be had it would be well of course to add same
to those waters.     I know of a lot of dams that I wish were
as well of <sic>off</sic> in fish food this winter as I think Mina dam is
with its fine depth and size.</p>

	<p> The coming spring when we are in our 
fish hatchery work at Pickerel lake and other points I shall
make it a point to give Mina dam the once over for general
conditions and will be glad to contact you with them.</p> 
	
		<p> Mail addressed to Kampeska Hotel, Watertown, 
will always be forwarded to me.</p>
	
		  <p> Very truly yours,
		  Department of Game and Fish,
			R. L. Ripple
			Supt. of Fisheries,
			R. L. Ripple.</p>
</div1>

<div1>

							<p> Woonsocket, S. Dak. 4-20, 35.</p> 	

<p> Mr. Bob Ripple                         
Watertown, S. Dak.</p>
 

<p> Dear Bob:</p>

	<p> I presume you are busy with the work of getting out your pike
spawn and as we had some very bad weather just after you wrote me, we did not have the fish
you asked for at that time.</p>

	<p> The boys have done a lot of work here and at Lake Andes, and the last
few days, have taken a lot of fish out of the river and have stocked several of the lakes in
this part of the state.   We have about 60 or 70 thousand now in the hatchery storing ponds mostly 4 inch bullheads, and about 4 or 5 hundred breeder croppies which we intend to use in this end of the state.  We have also about 2 or 3 thousand larger breeder bullheads that we are going to use in stocking.</p>

	<p> We may have a load or two to spare later and if we do I will let you
know and when you have spare time you can run down and get them.    I believe though that
you could get them closer through Curtis or Liebig over west of you on the Jim as they are 
plentiful along the Jim river most anywhere.    The 4 inch stuff is a little underfed due 
to their being so numerous but when placed in a lake where they get more food they make a very
fast growth.</p> 

	<p> The netting you ordered (1/2 inch I believe) was very good and boys
were wishing they had about 35 lbs <sic>lbs.</sic> more of it so they could make a hundred foot seine to get out this little stuff.   They have the lead and the floats here to make it up.   I wish you would order that amount of it and have them rush it out at once.</p>

	<p> Was over to Sioux Falls with a stock of bass for their lake out of ther <sic> out there</sic> and they were very much pleased.</p>

	<p> Have had some very good snow and rain and hope this dry weather will 
be a thing of the past soon.</p>

<p>Say Hello to <unclear reason="illegible" />.</p>           

                                     <p> Very truly,</p>
							
                                     <p> Dr Fankhauser</p>
</div1>

<div1>

										<p> Lake Andes, S. D.</p>
										<p> Jan. 4th, 1935.</p>

<p> Mr. R. L. Ripple,</p> 

<p> Watertown, S. D.</p> 

<p> Dear Bob:</p>         

		      <p> Inclosed please find report on the Lake Andes Hatcheries,
for 1934. have <sic>Have</sic> got a few Blue Gills left to plant, will take them to Woonsocket
Twin Lakes. Was unable to take care of the two dams at Gregory &amp; Iona,</p> 
	 		<p> I have 200 breeder bass &amp; 500 breeder Blue-gills in the 
north pond for the winter.</p>

				<p> Very truly yours,</p>
				<p> E. E. Allgier, Warden.</p> 
</div1>

<div1>

                        <p> June 22, 1934 </p>  

<p> Duffy to take care of fall 1934 with Bass</p>

<p> Mr. Ripple
Superintendent of Fish Hatcheries
Pierre, South Dakota</p>

<p> My dear Sir:</p>

	<p> I am writing you at the request of
several of the sportsmen and fishermen residing
in Clay County, South Dakota, who are interested
in stocking Swan Lake, located about twelve miles
straight North of Wakonda, Clay County, South
 Dakota, which lake is over the line in Turner 
County. You, no doubt, are aquainted with the lake.</p>

	<p> This lake even during the dry times
has had from six to eight feet of water the year
around, and at the present time, the water is going
over the spillway, and it seems to me it would be an
ideal lake for both pike and bass. There are a few
bass and pike in the lake now, but bullheads, perch,
croppies and sunfish are the most abundant, and are
caught out of the lake at the present time. I believe
that to restock this place with bullheads would make 
it a very profitable investment as this is the only
lake for a radius of 100 miles that a person can
catch fish.</p>

	<p> I would appreciate it very much to hear 
from you as to what kind of fish you have on hand
at the present time, and if there is any information
that I can furnish you, do not hesitate to call on
me as I will be very glad to get the information you
desire.</p>
	
					<p> Yours very truly</p>
					<p> Norman Joquith</p> 

<p> NJ/E</p> 
</div1>

<div1>

					<p> Huron, September 22, 1934.</p>

<p> Duffy Allgier,
Lake Andes, South Dakota.</p>

<p> Dear Duffy:</p>

	<p> Was glad to have you say you could get some
bass fingerlings over to Swan lake at Viborg since the
folks down around Vermillion have been asking about stocking
that lake since it is the only one they have in that whole
territory.   Our big Ford truck left here this morning with
bass for Flandreau, Baltic and Garretson dams while the Ford
Pickup took bass at the same time for Lake Chappelle at Highmore
and this finishes up our bass pond north of here except that
tomorrow morning we will truck about 3,000 fingerlings to
Pickerel and Enemy Swim lakes.   A number of other shiptments <sic>shipments</sic>
have been made including 600 which Fred Curtis the warden took
down to Lake Mitchell the other day.</p> 

	<p> Mr. O. H. Johnson is arranging to have a lot of
bass fingerlings trucked to west river country dams from our
Redfield ponds however we dont<sic>don't</sic> know until we get over there
next week Tuesday and get the ponds drawn down, just what we
can expect to have from that hatchery so I am glad you have
not to date drawn down your ponds so in case we are short at
Redfield we possibly can draw on your supply in part for some of
the places Mr. Johnson has in mind.      I am to hear from him
today about this matter of west river dams.</p> 

	<p> As soon as we get to Redfield and can extimate <sic>estimate</sic> our
supply of fingerlings I will let you know at once however I
know that you can stock the Platte lake and Swan lake and 
other places you are in the habit of stocking with bass like
Lake Henry at Scotland etc. but of course you dont <sic>don't</sic> know what
numbers you will have either until your ponds are drawn down. </p> 
   
	<p> Will keep in touch with you next week and if for
any reason you want to get in touch with me address or phone
in care Elmer Liebig, Lakeside bass hatchery, Redfield anytime
after next Monday as I will be there Monday night on through
the week.</p> 

					<p>Very truly yours,</p>
					<p> R. L. Ripple</p>
</div1>

<div1>

					<p> Watertown, September 24, 1934.</p>

<p> Mr. E. E. Allgier,
Lake Andes, South Dakota.</p>

<p> Dear Duffy:</p>

	<p> If you will please refer to my letter September 22nd,
you will notice I expected a letter from Director Mr. O. H. 
Johnson in reference to the distribution of bass fingerlings
from our  various bass hatcheries and I received said communication
here at Watertown last night.</p>

	<p> Mr. Johnson has suggested that a major portion of
this years <sic>year's</sic> output of bass fingerlings from the Huron, Redfield,
Woonsocket and Lake Andes hatcheries be placed in natural lakes 
with the exception that a few of the artificial lakes should be
stocked with some stuff as Lake Chappelle south of Holabird,
Lake Platte, Lake Mitchell, Kennebec in Lyman county, Scotland
Lake and possibly three or four in Deputy Bristol's territory,
also Lake Burke in George county.   His further suggestion is
that although a number of new artificial lakes have filled with
water this season we will adhere to our policy that the introduction
of fish other than bullheads be withheld for one full season after
an artificial lake fills up thus giving plant life an opportunity
to become established.</p>

	<p> Since you have not drawn down your ponds and we dont <sic>don't</sic>
know until the middle of the present week what we will have at
our Redfield hatchery we probably better keep in touch so as
soon as I lower the Redfield ponds starting tonight I will let
you know and will appreicate <sic>appreciate</sic> if you would drope me a line in care
of warden Elmer Liebig at Redfield what your prospects are.
We had a wonderful hatch at the Redfield ponds however the menace
of ducks and other water fowl has been great this season so we
are not so sure until the water is lowered.</p>

	<p> We stocked 800 bass fingerlings in the Chappelle lake
and 700 in Lake Mitchell from our Huron pond so in case you are
short of bass these stockings will be plenty especially that at
Chappelle lake.      Lake Mitchell of course can stand more bass in
case you have them over and above the other waters that will be
convenient to stock from your hatchery as Platte lake, Kennebec
lake in Lyman county, Scotland lake and Burke lake in Gregory county.
Also Swan lake at Viborg since they are hot for some bass and this
lake I understand is running over the outlet. From the Redfield
hatchery we expect to take a big load out into Deputy Bristol's
territory.</p> 
</div1>

<div1>

<p> Duffy Allgier 2,</p>

	<p> We have taken care of our natural lakes from the
Huron bass pond as Pickerel, Enemy Swim, Big Stone, Lake Cockran
with good stockings of bass so aside from Kampeska lake we
havent <sic>haven't</sic> any others in shape to receive fish and Kampeska being
so low this fall and not being a bass lake unless filled because
of no vegetation etc. we are caught up on natural lakes except
the Swan lake you will take care of.</p>

	<p> I am enclosing a couple of fish applications from 
Gregory county and hope you can do something about them but if
not kindly mail them back soon so I can have them on file in case
something turns up that we can fill them from some other source.</p>

	<p> Might further mention that Attorney J. C. Graber of
Freeman, S. D. wrote me saying their lake is full southeast of
Freeman that is supplied from Turkey Ridge creek and is about 20
to 30 acrea <sic>acres</sic> in extent.   Since this Turkey Ridge creek is spring
water they are thinking of trout and also suggest pike etc.
They state that they have already stocked crappies, SUNFISH, to <sic>too</sic> bad
about the sunfish, bluegills and bullheads obtained from the 
James river and now they ask what varieties of fish should be
introduced.   It is difficult for me to get away down there to
talk over matters with them and if at any time it is convenient
for you to do this it would be fine.    This lake of course has 
vegetation started from the creek that runs through it but I dont <sic>don't</sic>
know what to suggest about placing any bass in there this fall.
Thats <sic>That's</sic> why I think it would be well if you could contact the lake
and give them your ideas and tell them as I did in my reply not to
get any more SUNFISH in there.</p> 
		
			<p> Will keep in touch with you.</p>

						<p> Very truly yours,</p>

						<p> R. L. Ripple</p> 
</div1>


<div1>
				
						<p> Watertown, June 7, 1934.</p>
<p> Mr. E. E. Allgier
Lake Andes, South Dakota.</p>

<p> Dear Mr. Allgier:</p>

	<p> Since the time is drawing near when 
I will be making up the report of fish handled during
the past year, you will kindly make up a list of fish
sent out from your hatchery.</p>

	<p> Was sorry to learn you had such bad
luck with the bass breeders during last winter and when
we got to the Fair Grounds pond this spring we found
a big loss of bass breeders I presume from the same cause.
The new artesian well there kept an open space all through
the winter with plenty of depth and the bluegills came
through fine however the large bass went fluey.</p>

	<p> We are having a wonderful bass hatch at our
Redfield hatchery and expect a fair hatch from what breeders
I had left to devote to the Byron lake bass pond north of
Huron.    Had expected a fine hatch of bluegills at the Fair
Grounds pond however the well has retarded its flow so that 
along with the drought,the pond has gone down to the point
where we may have to take everything out.</p>

	<p> Had a wonderful hatch of pike fry at both
the Pickerel lake and Kampeska hatcheries this spring.</p> 

	<p> Hoping things are going along as well as 
can be expected during the drought and hard times, we have
heaps of rain up here, it just rains about every ten minutes
the past several days.</p>  

			<p> Very truly yours,</p>
			 <p> R. L. Ripple</p>
</div1>

</body>
</text>
</TEI> 
