<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.2.0/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="cdn.water.boat.0021">
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title level="m" type="main">Road Inspector To Go Over Every Route</title>
<title level="m" type="sub"></title>
<principal n="Nesheim, David A.">David Nesheim</principal>
</titleStmt>

<editionStmt>
<edition><date>2012</date></edition>
</editionStmt>
<publicationStmt>
<idno>cdn.water.boat.0021</idno>
 <authority>Casting Digital Nets: Fishery Modeling, Native Dispossession, and Dynamic History on the Great Plains</authority>
<distributor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln Libraries</distributor>
<address>
<addrLine>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</addrLine>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
<availability>
<p>Copyright &#169; 2012 by University of Nebraska, all rights reserved.
Items in the Archive may be shared in accordance with the Fair Use provisions
of U.S. copyright law.  Redistribution or republication on other terms, in
any medium, requires express written consent from the editor and advance
notification of the publisher, the Center for Digital Research in the Humanities.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>

<notesStmt>
<note type="summary">

</note>
</notesStmt>


<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="a" type="supplied">Road Inspector To Go Over Every Route</title>
<title level="a" type="original">Untitled</title>
<title level="j">Spencer News</title>
<author></author>
<publisher></publisher>
<pubPlace></pubPlace>
<date when="1907-06-20"></date>
<biblScope type="page">5</biblScope>
</bibl>
</sourceDesc>

</fileDesc>

<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="water">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="sky">
<term></term>
</keywords>
 <keywords scheme="original" n="land">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="earth">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="keyword">
<term>Road inspector</term>
</keywords>
</textClass>
</profileDesc>

<revisionDesc>
    <change when="2012-11-13"><name>Laura Weakly </name> Supplied title</change>
    <change when="2010-06-01"><name>Erin Pedigo</name> Initial Encoding</change>
    <change when="2010"><name>Sam Herley</name> OCR</change>

</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>

<text>


<body>
<div1>

<p>An inspector has been appointed by the government to inspect all roads on which the rural mail carriers travel and he will go over every route and inspect the condition of the roads and if he reports unfavorably the routes will be discontinued at once. It behoves the patrons of the rural routes to look after the good road proposition and see to it that the road traveled by the mail carrier is in a passable condition.</p>

<p>L. J. Radcliffe has the honor of having caught the largest black bass on this end of the lake this season, a 6 1/2 pounder, which he landed last Friday.</p>

<p>The management of the Belle of Andes has fitted the boat with roll side curtains and other fixtures thereby making it the coolest place to be found on the lake front. The lower deck is fitted up as a dining room where fishermen may eat their fill of savory fish fries at reasonable prices. The boat has been making successful trips up the lake and parties who wish to charter the boat for picnic excursions or runs up the lake can do so by addressing Carl Wendel, Lake Andes.</p>
</div1>

</body>
</text>
</TEI>