<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.2.0/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="cdn.land.resort.0007">
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title level="m" type="main">A Trip To Lake Andes</title>
<title level="m" type="sub"></title>
<principal n="Nesheim, David A.">David Nesheim</principal>
</titleStmt>
<editionStmt>
<edition><date>2012</date></edition>
</editionStmt>
<publicationStmt>
<idno>cdn.land.resort.0007</idno>
 <authority>Casting Digital Nets: Fishery Modeling, Native Dispossession, and Dynamic History on the Great Plains</authority>
<distributor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln Libraries</distributor>
<address>
<addrLine>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</addrLine>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
<availability>
<p>Copyright &#169; 2012 by University of Nebraska, all rights reserved.
Items in the Archive may be shared in accordance with the Fair Use provisions
of U.S. copyright law.  Redistribution or republication on other terms, in
any medium, requires express written consent from the editor and advance
notification of the publisher, the Center for Digital Research in the Humanities.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>

<notesStmt>
<note type="summary">

</note>
</notesStmt>


<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="a" type="original">A Trip To Lake Andes</title>
<title level="j">Spencer News</title>
<author></author>
<publisher></publisher>
<pubPlace></pubPlace>
<date when="1906-06-28"></date>
<biblScope type="page">5</biblScope>
</bibl>
</sourceDesc>

</fileDesc>

<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="water">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="sky">
<term></term>
</keywords>
 <keywords scheme="original" n="land">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="earth">
<term></term>
</keywords>
</textClass>
</profileDesc>

<revisionDesc>
    <change when="2010-02-18"><name>Laura Weakly</name> Initial Encoding</change>
    <change when="2010"><name>Sam Herley</name> OCR</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>

<text>


<body>
<head type="main">A TRIP TO LAKE ANDES</head>

<p>Last Friday in company with Treasurer Evers, Auditor Gibson and
Clerk Rouse ye editor went to Lake Andes on a fishing excursion. We
returned on a Saturday evening with seventy-five fish and well
pleased with our catch and with the enjoyment we had throughout the 
trip. Our stay at the lake was made most pleasant by the courtesy
of some of the business men of Lake Andes. Mr. T.E. Andrews supplied
us with boats and fish-poles. Mr. W.B. Gilreath took us down to the
lake and showed us where and how to catch fish. A. Vander Voort and
Editor Thompson came down to the lake late in the evening to help 
us care for the fish we had caught and the next morning Albert 
Amundson took us for a six mile ride in his gasoline launch which
he has recently constructed. This craft is 28 feet long and skips
through the water propelled by a three horse gasoline engine. The
boat will carry fifteen persons. Other parties are remodeling the
machinery on the Latham excursion boat and this boat too will soon
be at the service of pleasure seekers on the lake.</p>
<p>Lake Andes is a model place for an outing and in the near future
will be known far and wide as a pleasure resort which good fishing 
and good hunting will insure.&#8212;Wheeler Courier.</p>

</body>
</text>
</TEI>