<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.2.0/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="cdn.water.boat.0005">
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title level="m" type="main">Fourth of July Celebrated at Lake Andes</title>
<title level="m" type="sub"></title>
<principal n="Nesheim, David A.">David Nesheim</principal>
</titleStmt>
<editionStmt>
<edition><date>2012</date></edition>
</editionStmt>
<publicationStmt>
<idno>cdn.water.boat.0020</idno>
 <authority>Casting Digital Nets: Fishery Modeling, Native Dispossession, and Dynamic History on the Great Plains</authority>
<distributor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln Libraries</distributor>
<address>
<addrLine>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</addrLine>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
<availability>
<p>Copyright &#169; 2012 by University of Nebraska, all rights reserved.
Items in the Archive may be shared in accordance with the Fair Use provisions
of U.S. copyright law.  Redistribution or republication on other terms, in
any medium, requires express written consent from the editor and advance
notification of the publisher, the Center for Digital Research in the Humanities.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>

<notesStmt>
<note type="summary">

</note>
</notesStmt>


<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="a" type="supplied">Fourth of July Celebrated at Lake Andes</title>
<title level="a" type="original">Untitled</title>
<title level="j">Spencer News</title>
<author></author>
<publisher></publisher>
<pubPlace></pubPlace>
<date when="1906-07-05"></date>
<biblScope type="page">5</biblScope>
</bibl>
</sourceDesc>

</fileDesc>

<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="water">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="sky">
<term></term>
</keywords>
 <keywords scheme="original" n="land">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="earth">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="keyword">
<term>Fourth of July</term>
</keywords>
</textClass>
</profileDesc>

<revisionDesc>
    <change when="2012-11-14"><name>Laura Weakly</name> Fixed title</change>
    <change when="2010-06-01"><name>Erin Pedigo</name> Initial Encoding</change>
    <change when="2010"><name>Sam Herley</name> OCR</change>

</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>

<text>


<body>
<div1>

<p>Of the many quiet ways devised for the celebration of the Fourth, there
is perhaps no crowd of people who had a more enjoyable time, than the picnic
partys on the lake. Gaily decked out in colors the Belle of Andes at ten
in the morning, taking a large crowd to the upper end of the lake, and 
returned to take the second load. On the arrival at the upper end the big boat
was moored while a gay and jolly party of some thirty-five persons crowded
into the large sailing sloop of Messrs. Warren, Donovan and Yeager, which
had been towed up for their convenience and sailed merrily away on a 
voyage of discovery. The craft having been provisioned by the ladies.
The welcome cry of Land Ho, soon sounded from our look out, who had
climbed the mast and perched himself on the main-To-gallant mizzen fore
sheets somewhere about the crow's nest, just which we were unable to determine,
not being acquainted with sailors nomeclature, and being somewhat dizzy
from various nautical terms that were being bandied about by Captain
Warren and Look-out Yeager. Such as haul in the main braces, clew up that
To gallant, hold her up to the weather and haul in the slack, which by the way must
have been the slack in his suspenders, it being mess time. The land in
question proved to be an island, commonly known as Johnson's. The eagle eye of
Ed having discovered no signs of cannibals, it was decided to land. But a new
predicament arose, how could we release our lookout without his stepping
on some of our heads, as shinned down the pole or mast. This was solved by 
our noble captain, who rising to the occasion, threw out some sky hooks, rigged
up some block and tackle and lowered from his perilous position. On landing
lunch was served by the ladies committee, which turned out to be the best picnic
lunch it has ever been our good fortune to partake of, after which were 
various sports, with every one participating, until the arrival of the Belle
of Andes at dusk. </p>

<p>When the return trip by moonlight was commanded. The
big sail boat was commenced. The big sail boat towing along side, there being
insufficient win for sailing. Colored lights, roman candles, rockets continued to
unfold their brilliant colors as fast as the torch could be applied, until within
a mile of the shore, when at the request of the fire works commmitte the big
boat was stopped and the balance of the fire works let off in one 
grand display, until it appeared as though the very lake itself must
burn. At the conclusion of this we again weighed anchor, and pulled home,
arriving along side the dock at 12 p.m. To one standing on the landing the 
disembarkation by lantern light, in the neighborhood of a hundred people with 
their picnic basksets, and bundles, looked for all the world like the unloading
of the steam wherrys that convey the emmigrants from the Atlantic liners to 
Castle Garden. All extend thanks to the management of the Belle of Andes, for a 
delightful trip. It is impossible here to give the names of all who attended, so 
we merely mention the various committees and thank the ladies for their glorious
spread (Ye gods could we but sit to such a spread again.) Committee, Picnic No. 1,
Mesdames Andrews, VanderVoort and Qualey. In conclusion we wish to inform the 
public generally that the Belle of Andes can be chartered at any time except
Sunday for private parties, at a reasonable price. On Sundays the boat makes two
trips leaving Lake Andes at 10 a.m., and 2:30 p.m., the round trip being fifty cents.</p>
</div1>

</body>
</text>
</TEI>