<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.2.0/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="cdn.water.boat.0026">
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title level="m" type="main">Vessel Turns Over</title>
<title level="m" type="sub"></title>
<principal n="Nesheim, David A.">David Nesheim</principal>
</titleStmt>

<editionStmt>
<edition><date>2012</date></edition>
</editionStmt>
<publicationStmt>
<idno>cdn.water.boat.0026</idno>
 <authority>Casting Digital Nets: Fishery Modeling, Native Dispossession, and Dynamic History on the Great Plains</authority>
<distributor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln Libraries</distributor>
<address>
<addrLine>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</addrLine>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
<availability>
<p>Copyright &#169; 2012 by University of Nebraska, all rights reserved.
Items in the Archive may be shared in accordance with the Fair Use provisions
of U.S. copyright law.  Redistribution or republication on other terms, in
any medium, requires express written consent from the editor and advance
notification of the publisher, the Center for Digital Research in the Humanities.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>

<notesStmt>
<note type="summary">

</note>
</notesStmt>


<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="a" type="supplied">Vessel Turns Over</title>
<title level="a" type="original">Untitled</title>
<title level="j">Spencer News</title>
<author></author>
<publisher></publisher>
<pubPlace></pubPlace>
<date when="1908-07-16"></date>
<biblScope type="page">5</biblScope>
</bibl>
</sourceDesc>

</fileDesc>

<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="water">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="sky">
<term></term>
</keywords>
 <keywords scheme="original" n="land">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="earth">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="keyword">
<term>Lake story</term>
</keywords>
</textClass>
</profileDesc>

<revisionDesc>
    <change when="2012-11-13"><name>Laura Weakly </name> Supplied title</change>
    <change when="2010-06-01"><name>Erin Pedigo</name> Initial Encoding</change>
    <change when="2010"><name>Sam Herley</name> OCR</change>

</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>

<text>


<body>
<div1>


<p> Last Saturday evening Captain Bundy and First Mate Jack Moran put out from the Idle Hour Dock in the good ship "Queen of the Lake," with a goodly number of passengers who belonged to the Tabor ball team, bound for the camping ground chosen by the Tabor boys. The out voyage was a smooth one and the end was reached just before eight bells struck. The passengers and cargo were placed upon shore and the crew of the good ship put about for the return voyage. All went well until the vessel reached the south seas when a typhoon struck the fated ship, turning it completely over. The captain and mate had given up all hope but a flash of lightning revealed their peril to Life Station Captain Jud Frank who got out his life boat, attached his line, and with his life preservers, swiftly rowed to the scene of the wreck where he found the shipwrecked marines perched upon the rail of the boat calmly enjoying a smoke in the shelter of the hurricane deck apparently oblivious to their danger of a trip to Davy Jones' locker. With the assistance of the life saving crew the vessel was righted and towed to shore only about 100 yards distance. </p>
</div1>

</body>
</text>
</TEI>

