<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.2.0/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="cdn.water.boat.0001">
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title level="m" type="main">Wavelets</title>
<title level="m" type="sub"></title>
<principal n="Nesheim, David A.">David Nesheim</principal>
</titleStmt>
<editionStmt>
<edition><date>2012</date></edition>
</editionStmt>
<publicationStmt>
<idno>cdn.water.boat.0020</idno>
 <authority>Casting Digital Nets: Fishery Modeling, Native Dispossession, and Dynamic History on the Great Plains</authority>
<distributor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln Libraries</distributor>
<address>
<addrLine>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</addrLine>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
<availability>
<p>Copyright &#169; 2012 by University of Nebraska, all rights reserved.
Items in the Archive may be shared in accordance with the Fair Use provisions
of U.S. copyright law.  Redistribution or republication on other terms, in
any medium, requires express written consent from the editor and advance
notification of the publisher, the Center for Digital Research in the Humanities.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>

<notesStmt>
<note type="summary">

</note>
</notesStmt>


<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="a" type="original">Wavelets</title>
<title level="a"></title>
<title level="j">Spencer News</title>
<author></author>
<publisher></publisher>
<pubPlace></pubPlace>
<date when="1904-08-08"></date>
<biblScope type="page">4</biblScope>
</bibl>
</sourceDesc>

</fileDesc>

<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="water">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="sky">
<term></term>
</keywords>
 <keywords scheme="original" n="land">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="earth">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="keyword">
<term></term>
</keywords>
</textClass>
</profileDesc>

<revisionDesc>
    <change when="2012-11-14"><name>Laura Weakly</name> Fixed title</change>
    <change when="2010-06-01"><name>Erin Pedigo</name> Initial Encoding</change>
    <change when="2010"><name>Sam Herley</name> OCR</change>

</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>

<text>


<body>
<div1>

<head>WAVELETS</head>

<p>The safe for the Valley Bank was placed in position
today.</p>

<p>Miss Camillo Martin of Westfield, Ia., is a guest of 
Mr. &amp; Mrs. M. Qually.</p>

<p>The Wave desires a correspondent in every neighborhood
in the country. Write for terms.</p>

<p>E.H. Wood, of the State Bank at Lane, S.D., a new
bustling town 100 miles north of here, was in town last
evening the guest Mr. and Mrs. Amundson.</p>
<p>John Jirieck is among the enterprising men of town and 
by his work he shows his faith. He has a clean, up-to-
date meat market that would make some larger towns ashamed.</p>

<p>P.S. Everst, chief clerk and M.D. Colgrove, issue clerk
of the Yanktons at Greenwood, were in town Sunday, as was also
J.E. McCraig, one of the traders there, who incidentally took
in the ball game.</p>

<p>C.J. Allgood occupies part of teh Wave building exhibiting the
latest patterns of the cash register. His latest machine will
register a man's breath. So while he is in town don't give
yourself away.</p>

<p>"Teddy" Hinzeman was up from Wagner last night on his westward
trip for the Wagner Cigar Factory and left a good supply with our 
merchants. His factory will soon get out a "Lake Andes" brand.</p>

<p>G.M. Caster of Riverton, Neb. has been in town for several days 
and is seriously contemplating location here as an attorney. He
is a most agreeable gentleman and The Wave trusts he may decide
to remain.</p>

<p>David Dudley of Greenwood an Indian boy whom the Wave editor about
15 years ago taught to set type while superintendent for the Santee
Normal Training School renewed his acquaintance with the editor
Saturday.</p>

<p>The Wave has much enjoyed the companionship of M.E. Parham of Burr Oak,
Mich., a photographer of high merit and a young man of splendid character.
He is in the country partially for his health and with a view of location in 
the future.</p>

<p>A.M. Evans of Searsboro', la.. has been in town for a few days looking up
a location for a buisness [sic] and has about decided upon Lake Andes as
that location. His wife is a former educator in Iowa and will bring an 
experience whose quality is worthy of attention.</p>

<p>The Sioux Grain Company has its elevator well under way, but on Tuesday
was considerably delayed by reason of lumber delays. The foundation for
Major J.W. Harding's elevator is ready for the builders but the delay
of lumber is the same reason why his is not pushing ahead faster.</p>

<p>Wagner New Era, 29: Albert Amundson and family came from the Lake Monday
morning to finish packing their household goods, preparatory to moving
there to that town. He reports the town still growing, and predicts
that it will not be long till they have the largest town in the county.</p>

<p>O.M. McBaide of Tripp and Miss Bellows of Spirit Lake were the guests of 
the former's brother, A.G. McBribe, Sunday. They were delighted with the
location of Lake Andes, and Miss Bellows especially was surprised to see
such a growth in town building.</p>

<p>Rev. and Mrs. Peck, of Armour accompanied by their son and daughter were
in town Monday and purchased resident lots in the northwest part of the
town and are going to erect two dwellings this summer. They are pleased
with Lake Andes and satisfied to see the sun go down here in their
retirement.</p>

<p>Agent Ramsdall moved into his new quarters in the depot Wednesday morning
and he had an unusual smile for every patron when they congratulated him 
upon getting out of the old sweat box. The depot is similar to the Wagner 
station but some interior improvements not found in any of the older ones.</p>

<p>The following Armour visitors were in attendance at the baseball game
Saturday: Mrs. Roberts, Mrs. Kospers and mother, Mrs. Foster, Miss James,
Miss Dallie Sterns, Misses Kospers, Lizzie Roberts, Mr. Roberts, Mrs.
Boling, Lorice Boling, Beard Boling, Charles Black, Mr. Worer, Partie Sterns,
and Harry James.</p>

<p>Mr. and Mrs. Henry Steele and Mr. and Mrs. Frank
Frush of Tyndall were the guests of M.P. Steele
last week and on Sunday accompanied the Armour
people on their homeward lake trip on the Belle
of Andes. The return trip was by moonlight and
the pleasures of the trip with its variety of
excitement and novelties of navigation will be 
remembrances long to be related.</p>

<p>The Wave acknowledges editorial grips from Bros. Roy Tucker of the Geddes News,
V.A. Wecher of the Geddes Record and A.H. Pease of the Wagner New Era. A.J. 
Reichmann of the Record also handed out the grip with considerable vanity and
a faraway look, being the lucky printer to draw No. 136 in the Rosebud lottery.
O.P. Baker, H.D. Jelm and N.R. Reynolds were with Gedees editors.</p>

<p>The initial number of The Wave published here was eagerly sought last week. It 
was in the hands of every stranger, and those from the east came in for extra
copies to send home. "This is a pretty young town to have a newspaper," said
one gentleman, "and it's all right, for you are going to have a good town here.
The country surrounding Lake Andes justifies your enterprise and will support
it. I predict a thousand for your population in the next two years." In the 
meantime The Wave hopes to do its share of the pushing to that end and merit
a patronage that such service is entitled to. In way of suggestion, it will 
materially assist the editor if personal items of friends visiting any of
The Wave's readers, or any other items, are left at this office. A little
item may often serve for a text to a good local story, and this paper wants
the people its partners in the news. A subscription, of course, is always in
demand.</p>
</div1>

<div1>
<head type="main">THE BETTS GRADERS AT WORK</head>
<head type="sub">Depot Grounds Graded for Extra Trackage &#8212; Big Hotel Talk.</head>

<p>Betts Bros. grading gang pulled in here Saturday night and went into camp south
of the track. The grading of the depot grounds began Monday morning and 
excellent progress is being made toward levling up the premises preparatory to
beautifying them next spring. Additional trackage will be laid for the 
convenience of the five elevators to go up, three of which are already under
construction, the stockyards, coal sheds and water tank. Several weeks will
be occupied in finishing the work, and when completed it will make us appear
as if we were settling down to business.</p>

<p>"We are moving on the hotel project," said J.R. Arnold to The Wave itemizer, "and
as soon as Mr. Andrews returns from Oyster Bay we will bring the matter to a 
showdown. Andrews is warming up to the subject as he sees the necessity of a large
hotel, and it will be urged now."</p>
</div1>

<div1>
<head>YOUR PHOTO FREE</head>

<p>In order to introduce my work as a Photographer, I will give to ALL who come on next
Monday, Tuesday and Wednesday afternoon for NEXT WEEK ONLY a portrait of themselves
FREE. A.G. SCHMIDT GALLERY.</p>
</div1>

<div1>
<head type="main">RETURN OF THE ROSEBUD PILGRIMS</head>
	<head type="sub">Strangers Stop to See the Wonder Town Lucky County Men.</head>

<p>Many people are passing thro [sic] Lake Andes who are looking up
locations after becoming satisfied that their chances for a mansion
in the sky are better than one in Rosebud. "We like your get-up," said F.D.
Colgron of Algona, Ia., who, with N.S. Bruner of Chicago and F.E. Silvers of
Council Bluffs, drove over from Bonesteel Tuesday and took a fish in the lake
while their team rested. "It is simply beautiful about here, and a more 
desirable location for a town in this county could not be found. The soil
is here for a rich agricultural country, and there is none better anywhere than
right about Lake Andes."
"It surprises me," said Mr. Bruner, "that you have such a law-abiding class of 
people here, for I am told you are yet without organization in the town. It
speaks highly of the good sense of the population."</p>

<p>"No. 786 doesn't quite come up, to Platte's 8 nor Geddes' 36 in the Rosebud
drawing," remarked Irving Daly, "but Lake Andes is on the ground floor in the 
land selection. I shall go up in a few days and make my selection."</p>

<p>A.G. Schmidt's furniture store has a fine line of pictures and mouldings to 
frame them. Prices right.</p>

<p>Commodore Latham of the Belle of Andes has issued invitations to the editors
of Charles Mix and adjoining counties to mtake a spin on the lake August 11, 
accompanied by the families or best girls. The ocasion promises to be one of 
pleasure where we can chew the bait for the finny tribe instead of one another's
scalp. The visiting editors are reminded that this is forbidden ground and 
sarsaparilla is hard to pronounce when one's awfully dry.</p>

<p>Miss Martha and Master Lee Swett of Tyndall, sister and brother of Dr. Swett,
were guests of doctor and wife last week.</p>
</div1>
</body>
</text>
</TEI>