<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.2.0/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="cdn.land.resort.0005">
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title level="m" type="main">Senator Gamble in Town</title>
<title level="m" type="sub"></title>
<principal n="Nesheim, David A.">David Nesheim</principal>
</titleStmt>
<editionStmt>
<edition><date>2012</date></edition>
</editionStmt>
<publicationStmt>
<idno>cdn.water.boat.0020</idno>
 <authority>Casting Digital Nets: Fishery Modeling, Native Dispossession, and Dynamic History on the Great Plains</authority>
<distributor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln Libraries</distributor>
<address>
<addrLine>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</addrLine>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
<availability>
<p>Copyright &#169; 2012 by University of Nebraska, all rights reserved.
Items in the Archive may be shared in accordance with the Fair Use provisions
of U.S. copyright law.  Redistribution or republication on other terms, in
any medium, requires express written consent from the editor and advance
notification of the publisher, the Center for Digital Research in the Humanities.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>

<notesStmt>
<note type="summary">

</note>
</notesStmt>


<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="a">Untitled</title>
<title level="a">Senator Gamble in Town</title>
<title level="j">Spencer News</title>
<author></author>
<publisher></publisher>
<pubPlace></pubPlace>
<date when="1906-04-19"></date>
<biblScope type="page">5</biblScope>
</bibl>
</sourceDesc>

</fileDesc>

<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="water">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="sky">
<term></term>
</keywords>
 <keywords scheme="original" n="land">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="earth">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="keyword">
<term>Streets</term>
</keywords>
</textClass>
</profileDesc>

<revisionDesc>
    <change when="2012-11-14"><name>Laura Weakly</name> Fixed title</change>
    <change when="2010-02-18"><name>Laura Weakly</name> Initial Encoding</change>
    <change when="2010"><name>Sam Herley</name> OCR</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>

<text>


<body>
<head type="main"></head>

<head type="sub"></head>

<p>Senator Gamble was in town for a short time Friday afternoon, calling
on friends.</p>
<p>Mr. and Mrs. J.W. Hewett went to Tyndall Wednesday morning, returning
the same evening.</p>
<p>Miss Sadie Anderson came up from Vermillion Friday evening to spend
Easter at home.</p>
<p>John Stedronsky came up from Wagner on business Monday, returning Tuesday.
Attorney Dirks returned from a two weeks' visit with friends at Yankton,
Monday.</p>
<p>Stedronsky Bros. have a full line of machinery and hardware. See
their advertisement this week.</p>
<p>Roy Tucker and Date Raben were down from Geddes first of the week
hunting ducks.</p>
<p>Several prairie fires were burning east of town this week, and 
considerable property was destroyed, caused by some people being 
careless. People should be a little more careful about setting fires
unless there are good fire guards.</p>
<p>The Alpena Journal came out with eight pages of home print, 
containing a splendid write up of the town. When Brother Dye took
charge of the Journal plant six years ago it was practically a pile
of junk, he has made it one of the lceanest and best weekly 
newspapers of the state.</p>
<p>Belows Wood started for Texas Friday morning, he expects to purchase
several car loads of cattle to stock his farm east of town, which
he has fitted up in fine shape and where he has just put down an 
artesian well.</p>
<p>A citizen meeting was called Saturday evening to talk over the ...</p>


</body>
</text>
</TEI>