<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.2.0/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="cdn.land.letter.0001">
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title level="m" type="main">outboard motor letter</title>
<title level="m" type="sub"></title>
<principal>David Nesheim</principal>
</titleStmt>

<editionStmt>
<edition><date>2010</date></edition>
</editionStmt>
<publicationStmt>
<idno>cdn.land.letter.0001</idno>
 <authority>Casting Digital Nets: Fishery Modeling, Native Dispossession, and Dynamic History on the Great Plains</authority>
<distributor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln Libraries</distributor>
<address>
<addrLine>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</addrLine>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>etcenter@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
<availability>
<p>Copyright &#169; 2010 by University of Nebraska, all rights reserved.
Items in the Archive may be shared in accordance with the Fair Use provisions
of U.S. copyright law.  Redistribution or republication on other terms, in
any medium, requires express written consent from the editor and advance
notification of the publisher, the Center for Digital Research in the Humanities.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>

<notesStmt>
<note type="summary">

</note>
</notesStmt>


<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="a">outboard motor letter</title>
<title level="a"></title>
<title level="j">correspondence</title>
<author></author>
<publisher></publisher>
<pubPlace></pubPlace>
<date when="1933-12-13"></date>
<biblScope type="page">unknown</biblScope>
</bibl>
</sourceDesc>

</fileDesc>

<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="water">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="sky">
<term></term>
</keywords>
 <keywords scheme="original" n="land">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="earth">
<term></term>
</keywords>
</textClass>
</profileDesc>

<revisionDesc>
<change when="2010-08-04"><name> Rhiannon Root</name> Proofread</change>
    <change when="2010-06-01"><name>Erin Pedigo</name> Initial Encoding</change>
    <change when="2010"><name>Sam Herley</name> OCR</change>

</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>

<text>

<body>
<div1>

<p>Watertown, December 13, 1933.</p>

 <p> Mr. Willard Crandall,
 4759 N. Maplewood Ave.,
 Chicago, Ill.</p>

<p> Dear Sir:

	Yours of December 2nd, to hand in reference to 
the use of outboard motors to introduce oxygen into low
water lakes, dams etc. and will say that we have had real
results from this method combined with other equiptment <sic>equipment</sic> as
air compressors etc.</p>

	<p>It can be readily seen that by kicking a stream of 
water up onto the ice and allowing it to run for some distance
then allowing it to run down through holes made here and there
is of vast importance among low water lakes etc. where fish
may be in distress from lack of oxygen wether <sic>whether</sic> this water be
pumped up by the use of outboard motors or pumps etc.
We have made use of the outboard motors to a great extent since
they are so easily moved from place to place although pumps 
of various sorts can be used for the same purpose.</p>

	<p> The present winter we will if weather is adverse
and heavy ice comes to our more shallow lakes and dams
make use of air compressors along with a large water pump
mounted with gas engine on a truck and a number of outboard
motors.</p>

				<p> Very truly yours,</p>
				<p> Department of Game and Fish,</p>

				<milestone unit="absent" />
        <p>R. L. Ripple</p>
				<p> Supt. of Fisheries,</p>

</div1>


<div1>

<p> Watertown, December 26, 1933.</p>

<p> Mr. Elmer Liebig,
Cottonwood lake hatchery,
Redfield, South Dakota.</p>

<p> Dear Mr. Liebig:

	Am sure sorry to learn the seine hauls
made with the 1,200 ft. of seine have not brought in more
fish from our small showing with short seine previous to
freeze-up however it may be with a green crew things have
not panned out as they should since here at Pelican lake we
had more or less difficulty until we got set but the past
week has been successful in that we have brought in some
26,000 lbs. of fish all kinds that have been passed out in
this county at the rate of about 25 lbs. to the family.
People get them at the county sheds here at Watertown and
they have had three men passing them out.   Saturday morning
they had five tons on hand but by two o'clock afternoon all
were gone.   Our largest single haul to date was 6 and one
half tons.</p>

	<p> This we do find, that cars etc. cant <sic>can't</sic> be
running around on the ice near or inside the hauls in these
shallow waters we are working because the least alarm is felt
by especially the carp and they get to other parts at once.
We have to close in on them quickly and drive with cars and
trucks with cans etc. attached to make a noise before making
the landing and it sure helps.   I can't imagine only getting
a meager amount of fish at Cottonwood lake with the amount of
seine being used however things may pick up, on the other hand
I suppose the county men are wondering why they don't get more
fish.</p> 

	<p> I would like to see this big seine we are using
at Pelican lake here pulled through your lake with the addition
of the driving in we do with certain hauls, I'll bet you would
see plenty of fish come to shore. Carp are darn wise and I am
just wondering if your seine being short, the fish don't run
around it before landing.   Anyway I can suggest that they
should be careful not to drive or alarm those carp inside the
hauls before landing.   Seining carp in shallow water is not like
getting them in deeper lakes, they just get wise at the least
alarm or noise and get away.      Should have at least 2,500 ft.
of seine on that job.      Getting our air compressors etc. in shape,
will see you very soon.</p> 

					 <p> Yours very truly
					"Compliments of the season"</p>

</div1>


<div1>

<p>Watertown, December 26, 1933.

Mr. Fred Curtis,
Deputy State Game Warden,
Huron, South Dakota.</p> 

<p> Dear Mr. Curtis:

	Am rather tardy answering yours of the
15th, inst., in reference to your findings and the Roswell
and Donahue dams, we have had our hands full here with
the seining operations at Pelican lake since we are making
use of relief labor on this project and it was some time
before we got things so everything corked right.
Our total for this past week was 26,000 pounds of fish mostly
carp and buffalo that were alotted out at 25 lbs. per
family throughout this county.   Having only 14 inches of
water under the ice we have made every minute count to get
the fish while we could work our big seine of about 3,500 ft.</p> 

	<p> Glad we did not get to send fish to fill
that Donahue application after all if they have no proper
place for them and read with great interest your findings
in reference to the Roswell dam which should be very O. K.
when finished. I find that the two flocks of about 4,000
pelicans each that fished Pelican lake here for two months
previous tot he freeze-up took this lake to a cleaning in
the matter of perch and bullheads, leaving the carp, buffalo and
northern pike so I wont have any application fish from this
source.      Think it may be well so long as they only have
three feet of water in the Roswell dam to wait until spring
and after the severe winter weather is over to stock their
waters when it can be done to a nicety with bullheads and a
few other varieties from our spring fishing operations.
Of course if I run onto a lot of bullheads some where we may
get them some this winter but that is doubtful now.
I have reserved about One half million bullheads of this last
years hatch in our bass ponds at Lake Andes and Redfield for
spring stocking of waters should we get water so we will be
all set along that line however I would not have much opportunity
to get into those ponds at this time.</p> 

	<p> To date we havent had any great success with
getting large seine hauls at either Lake Traverse or Cottonwood
lake at Redfiels but hope for better results from now on.
	Hope you had a fine  Christmas and wishing
you and yours a Happy New Year,</p> 

				<p> Very truly yours,</p> 

      <p>R. L. Ripple</p>

				     

</div1>

</body>
</text>
</TEI>
