<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.2.0/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="cdn.land.resort.0012">
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title level="m" type="main">Bundy Launch in Commission</title>
<title level="m" type="sub"></title>
<principal n="Nesheim, David A.">David Nesheim</principal>
</titleStmt>

<editionStmt>
<edition><date>2012</date></edition>
</editionStmt>
<publicationStmt>
<idno>cdn.water.boat.0020</idno>
 <authority>Casting Digital Nets: Fishery Modeling, Native Dispossession, and Dynamic History on the Great Plains</authority>
<distributor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln Libraries</distributor>
<address>
<addrLine>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</addrLine>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
<availability>
<p>Copyright &#169; 2012 by University of Nebraska, all rights reserved.
Items in the Archive may be shared in accordance with the Fair Use provisions
of U.S. copyright law.  Redistribution or republication on other terms, in
any medium, requires express written consent from the editor and advance
notification of the publisher, the Center for Digital Research in the Humanities.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>

<notesStmt>
<note type="summary">

</note>
</notesStmt>


<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="a">Untitled</title>
<title level="a">Bundy Launch in Commission</title>
<title level="j">Spencer News</title>
<author></author>
<publisher></publisher>
<pubPlace></pubPlace>
<date when="1909-05-27"></date>
<biblScope type="page">3</biblScope>
</bibl>
</sourceDesc>

</fileDesc>

<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="water">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="sky">
<term></term>
</keywords>
 <keywords scheme="original" n="land">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="earth">
<term></term>
</keywords>
</textClass>
</profileDesc>

<revisionDesc>
    <change when="2012-11-14"><name>Laura Weakly</name> Fixed title</change>
    <change when="2010"><name>Laura Weakly</name> Model Encoding</change>
    <change when="2010"><name>Sam Herley</name> OCR</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>

<text>


<body>


<p>J.H. Bundy once more has his launch in commission. It has been
treated to a new coat of paint and the engine overhauled and is now
one of the niftiest pleasure crafts on Lake Andes ...</p>

<p>Tri-County News &#8212; Ye Editor and the "Devil" returned from a very pleasant
fishing tour to Lake Andes last Monday night after an outing which
lasted from Friday until Tuesday of this week. To say that we
enjoyed our trip is putting the same mildly but we certainly did
not have the luck of former trips and those we promised a mess
of fish will have to be contented with "the next time we go." We
are sorry that we were not able to fetch home a greater amount
of the finny monsters of the beautiful Lake Andes. While in the town
of Lake Andes we were treated royally by our former townsman F.A.
Anderson who did everything in his power to make the trip pleasant
for us and we appreciate his efforts very much. We also met Mr. Rogers
of the Lake Andes Wave, who is the handy man around the office, 
and enjoyed a pleasant hour in the sanctum sanctorium of Brother
Corey. We shall not forget the trip to the Lake Town for these many
moons and hope in the very near future to return to get more of
the finny tribe.</p>

</body>
</text>
</TEI>